—— 微分享US字幕组 ——
—— www.universesharing.net ——
感谢 笑笑笑 jaejis tictaclu 莙。 獨一無二 翻译
校订了一夜的倒霉MC 校订
Subtitles downloaded from Podnapisi.NET
硝烟的战场
[Terrible battle and  cannons noise]
我们之中有些人是美国堪萨斯混合部队的
HAROLD GREEN:  Some of us
was in the Second Kansas Colored.
上哥四月份我们在Jenkins的渡口跟南军士兵打了一仗
We fought the rebs at
Jenkins’ Ferry last April,
在之后，他们把俘虏的黑人士兵毒死在毒笼里
just after they’d killed every Negro
soldier they captured at Poison Springs.
就在Jenkins的渡口
So at Jenkins’ Ferry,
我们决定警醒一下这件事
we decided warn’t taking no reb prisoners.
我们不能丢下任何活着的士兵
And we didn’t leave a one of ‘em alive.
某一天我们也可能会这样
The ones of us that didn’t die that day,
长官，我们已经与第116号美国混血人汇合
we joined up with the116th U.S.
Colored, sir.
从Camp Nelson肯塔基州
From Camp Nelson Kentucky.
你叫什么名字，士兵？
LINCOLN: What’s your name, soldier?
Private Harold Green，长官
Private Harold Green, sir.
我叫Corporal Ira Clark，长官
I’m Corporal Ira Clark, sir.
第五马萨诸塞州骑兵队
Fifth Massachusetts Cavalry.
我们在那里等
We’re waiting over there.
我们留在马队的后面
We’re leaving our horses behind,
跟24步兵队离开
and shipping out with the 24th Infantry
为了下星期在Wilmington作战
for the assault next week on Wilmington.
你成为士兵多久了？
LINCOLN: How long’ve you been a soldier?
两年了，长官
Two year, sir.
第二堪萨斯混合步兵
LINCOLN: Second Kansas Colored Infantry,
他们在Jenkins渡口很勇敢的战斗
they fought bravely at Jenkins’ Ferry.
是的，长官
That’s right, sir.
他们歼灭了一千名叛军，长官
They killed a thousand
rebel soldiers, sir.
他们很勇猛
They were very brave.
每个月拿着比白种士兵少3美金的军粮
And making three dollars less
each month than white soldiers.
美国第二堪萨斯部队的小伙子们...
Us 2nd Kansas boys...
从我们制服定制的花费中减少3美金
Another three dollars subtracted
from our pay our pay for our uniforms.
收到，长官，但是...
That was true, yes sir, but....
同等的薪酬，但是不包括黑人少尉以上的军官
Equal pay now, but still no
commissioned Negro officers.
我知道那些，Corporal Clark
LINCOLN: I am aware of that, Corporal Clark.
遵命，这是你了解到的好的方面
Yes, sir, that’s good you’re aware, sir.
只是这...
It’s only that...
你认为Wilmington战役。。。
LINCOLN: Do you think
the Wilmington attack...
既然那些白人已经习惯于
Now that white people have
accustomed themselves
黑人拿起枪炮为了他们的利益而战
to seeing Negro men with guns,
fighting on their behalf,
而且他们可以接受黑人士兵得到相同的薪酬
and now that they can tolerate
Negro soldiers getting equal pay,
也许许多年后，他们会容忍黑人中尉跟上尉的命令
maybe in a few years they can abide the
idea of Negro lieutenants and captains.
在五十年后，也许有黑人上校
In fifty years, maybe a Negro colonel.
一百年后...选举.
In a hundred years... the vote.
战后你有什么打算,Corporal Clark?
What’ll you do after the war,
Corporal Clark?
工作，长官
CLARK: Work, sir.
或许你会雇佣我
Perhaps you’ll hire me.
也许我会
Perhaps I will.
但是你应该知道，长官，我有病
But you should know, sir, that I get sick
一身焦味，还没法剪发
at the smell of boot black
and I cannot cut hair.
我发现一个人可以帮我剪发而且很不一般
I’ve yet to find a man could cut
mine so it’d make any difference.
你剪了有弹性的头发
CLARK: You got springy hair for a white man.
是的，我的最后一位理发师做的
Yes, I do. My last
barber hanged himself.
就是之前的那个
And the one before that.
在他的西港岛线给我留下了他的剪刀
Left me his scissors in his will.
[Green laughs]
林肯总统？
– FIRST WHITE SOLDIER: President Lincoln, sir?
晚上好，小伙子们
– Evening, boys.
SECOND WHITE SOLDIER:
我们看见你在，额，我们...
We saw you at, um, we...
我们来自，嗯，来自
– We were at, uh, at...
我们来自盖茨堡
– We was at Gettysburg!
你们这些小伙子们在盖茨堡打过仗？
You boys fight at Gettysburg?
没有，我们没有在那里参加过战斗
Naw, we didn’t fight there.
我们上个月才入伍
We just signed up last month.
两年前我们在墓地奉献中见过他
We saw him two years ago
at the cemetery dedication.
对，我们听过你演讲
Yeah, we heard you speak,
我们，嗯...一点，一点点！
we, uh... ah damn, damn damn!
嘿，反正你们很高大
Uh, hey, how tall are you anyway?!
上帝啊，闭嘴！
Jeez, shut up!
你们能听到我说了什么吗？
Could you hear what I said?
没有，不是很多
FWS: No, sir, not much.
就是...
It was....
四轮成绩跟7年前
“Four score and seven years ago,
我们的父亲们在这片大陆创建了一个新的国家
our fathers brought forth
on this continent a new nation,
自由构想和宣告主张
conceived in liberty and
dedicated to the proposition
所有人都是平等的
that all men are created equal.
很好，谢谢
That’s good, thank you.
现在我们有内战
FWS: “Now we are engaged in a great civil war,
看看是否有些民族有一些如此的想法
testing whether that nation
or any nation so conceived
是否如此的想法可以长久
and so dedicated can long endure.
我们-我们-我们在战场上经历过
We are-we are-we are met
on a great battlefield of that war.”
很好，谢谢
That's good, thank you.
我们要开辟出一块疆土
SWS: “We have come to dedicate
a portion of that field
作为他们最后的栖息之所，是他们在这片赋予他们生命的土地上
as a final resting place for
those who here gave their lives
战斗并且赢得胜利。
that that nation might live.
那是...
– It is...”.
他的叔叔，
– His uncles,
他们在战争的第二天就牺牲了
they died on the second day of fighting.
我知道最后一部分。'那是...
I know the last part. “It is...
– VOICE: Company up! Move it out!
那相当...
– it is rather...
小伙子们，祝你们前途一片光明
LINCOLN: Boys, best go and
并且找到你们的伙伴。谢谢
find your company. Thank you.
非常感谢，先生
Thank you, sir.
上帝保佑你
God bless you.
上帝也保佑你们
LINCOLN: God bless you too.
我很有决心留下来
CLARK: “That we here highly resolve
不要做出无谓的牺牲
that these dead shall
not have died in vain.
这个国家，除上帝之外
That this nation, under God,
应该诞生一个新的自由
shall have a new birth of freedom,
人们自己成立的政府
and that government of the
people, by the people,
为了人民服务
for the people,
不应该消失于世界上
shall not perish from the earth.
这是夜间
LINCOLN: It’s nighttime.
由于能源问题，船的移动速度很不乐观
The ship’s moved by some terrible
power, at a terrific speed.
尽管在夜间感觉不到
Though it’s imperceptible in the darkness,
我有一种直觉，我们在面向岸边
I have an intuition that we’re
headed towards a shore.
没人看起来像在船上，而且我...
No one else seems to be
aboard the vessel and I...
我知道我很孤独
I'm kinny aware of my aloneness.
在坚强的外壳下我没有极限
LINCOLN: I could be bounded in a nutshell
我领头于极限
and count myself a king of infinite space
这并不是说我的梦想很不好
were it not that I have bad dreams.
我认为我的思想速度比较怪异
I reckon it’s the speed
that’s strange to me,
我常常研究步伐
I’m used to going a deliberate pace.
我应该饶恕你的，Mary。
I should spare you Mary,
我不应该告诉你我的梦想
I shouldn’t tell you my dreams.
如果你不说的话，我不想要被饶恕
MARY: I don’t want to be spared if you aren’t!
你没有赦免我
And you spare me nothing.
可能是...
MARY: Perhaps it’s...
这是Wilmington港口的战役
it’s the assault on Wilmington port.
在打仗前，你通常都会梦到船
You dream about the ship
before a battle, usually.
椰子怎么样？
How’s the coconut?
难以形容
Beyond description.
基本上两年没有进展
Almost two years, nothing mends.
战争的牺牲品
Another casualty of the war.
谁想听没用的女人去抱怨车祸？
Who wants to listen to a useless woman
grouse about her carriage accident?
我会。
你个怪胎。
– I do.
– Stuff!
你就是说了你的梦想，我是你的占星师。
You tell me dreams, that’s all,
I’m your soothsayer,
我再也不会那样了，没人相信我。
that’s all I am anymore,
I’m not to be trusted...
就算不是运输事故。
Even if it wasn’t a carriage accident,
即使它曾是蓄意暗杀事件。
even if it was an attempted assassination.
这也许是个...
MARY: 这是个暗杀。
– It was most probably an ass...
– MARY: It was an assassin,
以前是谁把你当靶子的。
whose intended target was you.
那个宴会的计划怎么样？
How’s the plans coming along
for the big shindy?
我懒得跟你说。
I don’t want to talk about parties.
MARY:你就懒得关心下party么。
MARY (CONT'D): You don’t care about parties.
也不是，但是他们无法避免的。
Not much but they’re a
necessary hindrance.
了解...
I know...
我知道那个船是神马情况了。
I know what it’s about, the ship.
那不是威明顿市的港口，
这可不是军事活动。
It's not Wilmington Port,
it’s not a military campaign!
那是废除奴隶制度的修正案。
It’s the amendment to abolish slavery!
你怎么也逼迫我邀请疯狂的激进分子来我家。
Why else would you force me to invite
demented radicals into my home?
MARY:你会尝试让修正案在众议院通过吧。
MARY: You’re gonna try to get the amendment
passed in the House of Representatives,
在这个学期结束前，在典礼开始以前。
before the term ends,
before the Inauguration.
在那上面别花太多银子了。
Don’t spend too much money
on the flub dubs.
没人给予我像你这么多的爱..
No one’s loved as much as you,
没人曾今被人们如此爱戴过。
no one’s ever been loved
so much by the people,
你还是做点什么吧
you might do anything now.
千万不要浪费精力在修正草案上了，肯定会失败的。
Don’t, don’t waste that power on an
amendment bill that’s sure to defeat.
你还记得Robert为了张收据在家里吗？
MARY: Did you remember Robert’s
coming home for the reception?
我知道你忘了。
I knew you’d forget.
那个就是你坐的船吧，第30号修正案。
That’s the ship you’re sailing on.
The Thirteenth Amendment.
不用你说我是对的，我懂的。
MARY: You needn’t tell me I’m right,
I know I am.
太晚了，Mrs.kekley.
Oh it’s late, Mrs. Keckley.
为了晚宴夫人需要这个
She needs this for the grand reception.
这是个细活。
It’s slow work.
晚安
Good night.
你跟她说了那个梦了没？
Did you tell her a dream?
爸爸？   嗯？
TAD: Papa? LINCOLN: Hmm?
爸爸，我想看看Willie.
Papa, I wanna see Willie.
我也想，taddie.但是没办法。
Me too, Taddie. But we can’t.
为什么不行的说？
Why not?
Willie 已经..三年前的今天他离开了. Willie’s gone.Three years now. He’s gone.
乐器演奏
Instrumental rendition of
“We Are Coming Father Abra’am.”
给我安排的这部分就是升旗..
The part assigned to me
is to raise the flag,
如果设备没有问题，我就升了。
which, if there be no fault
in the machinery, I will do,
什么时候升,它会为人们徐徐飘扬的。
and when up, it will be for
the people to keep it up.
那是我的台词。
That's my speech.
笑声+鼓掌声
[Audience laughing and applauding]
[乐队标语..]
‘We are coming Father Abra am’
three hundred thousand more
来自密西西比河的蜿蜒小溪，来自大不列颠的海岸。
From Mississippi’s winding stream
and from New England’s shore
我们留下了耕和工厂还有亲爱的老婆和孩子。
?We leave our plows and workshops
our wives and children dear
即使房子里所有人投了“yes,”
SEWARD: Even if every Republican
in the House votes yes,
远离了担保，何时起我们的全体一致支持点什么？
far from guaranteed, since when has
our party unanimously supported anything?
但是我们所有的伙伴给它投了票，
but say all our fellow
Republicans vote for it,
我们仍然只有20票。
We’d still be twenty votes short.
只有20票？
只有那么多。
– Only twenty?
– Only twenty!
我们能找到的只有20票了。
We can find twenty votes.
20个民主主义者里谁会投票废除奴隶制.
Twenty House Democrats
who’ll vote to abolish slavery,
我看的话...那些我经常听的。
in my opinion...
– To which I always listen.
或者假装一下，用我所有的三只耳朵。
– Or pretend to.
– With all three of my ears.
我们马上就要赢得战争了。这是没法避免的，是不？
We’ll win the war soon.
It’s inevitable, isn’t it?
还没有赢呢。
LINCOLN: Ain’t won yet.
你将会带着你的半神的高度开始你的第二轮了。
You’ll begin your second term
with semi-divine stature.
想想带来和平的可能性有多少。
Imagine the possibilities
peace will bring!
为什么要用一场战争去玷污你没有价值的光泽。
Why tarnish your invaluable luster
with a battle in the House?
那个里面大概就是老鼠的巢穴吧。
It’s a rats’ nest in there,
同一群无脑的村民..咋整
the same gang of talentless
hicks and hacks who
十个月以前就抵制修正案，我们就会失败。
rejected the amendment
ten months ago. We’ll lose.
我喜欢我们现在的机遇。
I like our chances now.
好吧，考虑到我们会面对的障碍。
SEWARD: Well, consider the
obstacles we would face.
上述三分之二的需要通过修正案。
The aforementioned two-thirds majority
needed to pass an amendment.
我们有一个共和党的主旨，但是几乎不会超过50%.
We have a Republican majority,
but barely more than fifty percent.
56个
LINCOLN: Fifty-six.
我们需要大众的支持啊。
We need Democratic support.
已经没有了哦。
There’s none to be had.
自从上次那个修正案的投票后，还有过一次投票。
Since the House last voted on
the amendment, there’s been an election.
64个民主党人失去了他们的地位在11月的选举，那是..
Sixty-four Democrats lost their
House seats in November, that’s...
64个民主党人正在找工作.
sixty-four Democrats looking for work
就是三月份
我知道。
come March
– I know.
他们不用担心那个复选。
They don’t need to worry
about re-election,
他们可以随便投票。
they can vote however it suits ‘em.
但是我们不能...
But we can’t, um...
[knocks on door]
给修正案买些选票来，那个太重要了。
buy the vote for the amendment,
it's too important.
敲门..
[Knocks on door]
我没说关于买卖的事情。
LINCOLN: I said nothing of buying anything.
我只说我们需要20个投票。
We need twenty votes was all I said.
开始我的第二轮吧，有充足的位置来填补。
Start of my second term,
plenty of positions to fill.
总统先生，容我介绍下来自Missouri的Jolly夫妇。
NICOLAY: Mr. President, may I present Mr.
and Mrs. Jolly who’ve come from Missouri to...
我们来自Jeff city，总统先生。
MR JOLLY: From Jeff City, President.
Jolly先生，女士。
LINCOLN: Mr. Jolly.
Ma'am.
这是国务卿苏厄德的离职时期.
This by the fire’s
Secretary of State Seward.
JEFF市。
Jeff City.
我听说过一个Jefferson市的律师的事情。
I heard tell once of a...
Jefferson City lawyer,
鹦鹉每天都会在早上把主人叫醒。
who had a parrot
that’d wake him each morning,
哭着说，今天是世界末日。
crying out, “Today is the day
the world shall end
正如圣经里面预测的。
as scripture has foretold.”
然后有一天，那个律师射杀了他。
And one day...
the lawyer shot him
为了和平和安详我推测...
for the sake of peace
and quiet, I presume,
因此感到满足，至少为了鸟儿，这是预言。
thus fulfilling, for the
bird at least, its prophecy.
在JEFF市只有一个过路收费亭，到西南的话。
There’s only one tollbooth in Jeff City,
to the southwest,
一个叫Heinz人，来自Rolla.
and this man Heinz Sauermagen from Rolla
非法占有接近2年，自从..
been in illegal possession
for near two year, since
你的人Schofield把他陷害了。
your man General Schofield
set him up there.
但是总统Monroe把收费站给了我爷爷
But President Monroe give
that toll gate to my granpap
和昆西...
and Quincy Adams...
给我的人民行动党一封信说这是我们的“永远"。
give my pap a letter saying
it’s our’n for keeps.
Jolly女士得到了那个...
Mrs. Jolly got the...
给Lincoln看看昆西的信。
Show Mr. Lincoln the Quincy Adams letter.
那没必要，Jolly女士。说说你要干嘛。
LINCOLN: That’s unnecessary, Mrs. Jolly.
Just tell me what you want from me.
Jolly得了肺气肿仍然抽雪茄烟。
Mr. Jolly’s emphysema
don’t care for cigars.
女士。你知道宪法下的第30号修正案吗？
Madame. Do you know about the proposed
Thirteenth Amendment to the Constitution?
我知道啊，每个人都知道。总统先生喜欢它。
Yes sir, everybody knows of it.
The President favors it.
但是你呢？
我们喜欢。
– But do you?
– We do.
你知道它是用来废除奴隶制度的吗？
You know that it abolishes slavery?
是的，先生。我知道它。
Yes sir. I know it.
这就是你为什么赞成它？
And is that why you favor it?
我赞成的是结束战争。
What I favor is ending the war.
一旦我们废除奴隶制，
南方的士兵们将会停止战斗，
Once’t we do away with slavery,
the rebs will quit fighting,
因为他们正是为奴隶制度来战斗的。
since slavery’s what they’re fighting for.
林肯先生，你总是这么说。
Mr. Lincoln, you always say so.
MRS JOLLY: 经过修订之后，当奴隶制度结束后，他们就会放弃了。
MRS JOLLY: With the amendment,
slavery’s ended and they’ll give up,
然后战争就将结束了。
the war can finish then.
如果战争先结束了，
在我们废除奴隶制度之前，
If the war finished first,
before we end slavery,
那么...
-林肯总统说
would...
– President Lincoln says
战争不会停止，除非
the war won’t stop unless
我们废除奴隶制度...
-但是...
we finish slavery...
– But...
如果这么做。
南方将消耗殆尽。
if it did.
The South is exhausted.
WEWARD：如果他们用尽子弹和男人，
SEWARD: If they run out of bullets and men,
你仍将执行你想要的，额...
would you still want your, uh...
谁是你的代表？
Who’s your representative?
LINCOLN: Jeff City?还是那个，呃，
Burton议员吗？
LINCOLN: Jeff City? That’s, uh,
Congressman Burton?
“瘦竹竿” Burton.我的意思是，
Josiah Burton。
“Beanpole” Burton. I mean,
Josiah Burton, yes.
林肯：共和党。在修正案的问题上面还犹豫不定，我想。
LINCOLN: Republican. Undecided on the
question of the amendment, I believe.
也许你可以叫上他，并告诉他你的热情。
Perhaps you could call on him
and inform him of your enthusiasm.
-好吧...
– SEWARD: 女士？
– Yeah...
– SEWARD: Madam?
如果反抗政府在下周投降，
If the rebels surrender next week,
你会在这个月底
would you, at the end of this month,
让Burton议员表决第十三号修正案？
want Congressman Burton to vote
for the Thirteenth Amendment?
如果这个通过，
就不再有战争了，
If that was how it was,
no more war and all,
我估计Mr. Jolly不会太赞同通过这个修正案。
I reckon Mr. Jolly’d much prefer not
to have Congress pass the amendment.
SEWARD:那么，呃．．． 为什么这样？
SEWARD: And, uh... why’s that?
黑鬼。
Niggers.
MRS. JOLLY: 如果它没有让一些亚拉巴马洲的黑人进入密苏里洲，
MRS. JOLLY: If he don’t have to let
some Alabama coon come up to Missouri,
偷走他的鸡和他的工作，
他也许会赞同它。
steal his chickens and his job,
he’d much prefer that.
该死的种族主义者！我开始明白为什么你想
这么快的通过这个法案。
The people! I begin to see why you’re
in such a great hurry to put it through.
先生，能让我研究这些，关于过路收费亭的信件吗？
Would you let me study this letter,
sir, about the tollbooth?
林肯：　我在早上回来，我们会考虑法律上说什么。
LINCOLN: Come back to me in the morning,
and we’ll consider what the law says.
林肯：我会去拜访那个“瘦竹竿”，
LINCOLN: And be sure to visit “Beanpole”,
告诉他你支持修正案的通过，
and tell him that you support
passage of the Amendment,
作为军事上的需要。
as a military necessity.
NICOLAY:谢谢。
NICOLAY: Thank you.
林肯：　哦， Nicolay,
当你有时间．．．
LINCOLN: Oh, Nicolay,
when you have a moment...
假如能用提供就业机会来获取投票，
If procuring votes with offers
of employment is what you intend,
我将接一个从奥尔巴尼来做间谍的朋友，
I’ll fetch a friend from Albany
who can supply the skulking men
在地下工作很有才能。
gifted at this kind of shady work.
原谅我对民主党的耻辱。
Spare me the indignity of
actually speaking to Democrats.
饶恕你的曝光。
Spare you the exposure and liability.
林肯：原谅我，那是一个遇难信号，
LINCOLN: Pardon me, that’s a distress signal,
我必须遵守庄严的誓言。
which I am bound by
solemn oath to respond to.
Tom Pendel拿开了Mr. Gardner发送过来的奴隶的玻璃牌
Tom Pendel took away the glass camera
plates of slaves Mr. Gardner sent over
因为Tom说他妈妈说他们太痛苦了，但是．．
because Tom says mama says
they’re too distressing, but...
你整夜都在做噩梦，
妈妈说的对．．．
You had nightmares all night,
mama’s right to...
我将有更严重的噩梦，如果你不再让我再看见那些牌子！
I’ll have worse nightmares, if you
don’t let me look at the plates again!
LINCOLN: 也许。
LINCOLN: Perhaps.
SEWARD: 我们承受不起我们党内任何一个背叛，
SEWARD: We can't afford a single
defection from anyone in our party,
甚至没有一个共和党人在投票的时候缺席。
not even a single Republican
absent when they vote.
你知道谁会拿去看
You know who you’ve got to see.
发送到布莱尔的屋里。
Send over to Blair House.
问布莱尔，我能在５点钟左右拜访他吗。
Ask Preston Blair can I call on him
around five o’clock.
愿老天保佑你
God help you.
只有上帝知道他将问你给他什么
God alone knows what
he’ll ask you to give him.
如果布莱尔告诉他们，没有共和党人会阻止修正案的投票。
If the Blairs tell ‘em to, no Republican
will balk at voting for the amendment.
MONTGOMERY BLAIR:　你的意思是没有保守的共和党人。
MONTGOMERY BLAIR: No conservative
Republican is what you mean.
PRESTON BLAIR:所有的共和党人应该保持传统，
PRESTON BLAIR: All Republicans
ought to be conservative,
我在我的家乡建立这个党派
I founded this party
in my own goddamned home
去成为一个保守的反对废除奴隶制度的党派，
to be a conservative antislavery party,
不是去变成一个该死的激进废除奴隶制度的党派。
not a hobbyhorse for
goddamned radical abolitionists.
ELIZABETH BLAIR:　爸爸，弄低点，别吓着孩子了。
ELIZABETH BLAIR: Damp down the
dyspepsia, daddy, you’ll frighten the child.
MONTGOMERY:你需要在我们在日常工作中站在党派的保守边
MONTGOMERY: You need us to keep the
conservative side of the party in the traces
当你骗取了激进党派，把Thaddeus Stevens的团伙包围起来
while you diddle the radicals and
bundle up with Thaddeus Stevens’s gang,
你需要我们的帮助。
－是的，先生，我需要。
you need our help.
– Yes, sir, I do.
－好吧，我们能得到什么？
– Well, what do we get?
– Whoo! Blunt!
你的举止，Monty,
为什么，林肯先生．．．
Your manners, Monty,
must be why Mr. Lincoln...
把你从他的内阁开除了。
– PRESTON:他被开除了。
pushed you out of his cabinet.
– PRESTON: He was pushed out.
－我没有被开除。
－喔，当然你没有。
– I wasn’t pushed.
– Oh of course you weren’t.
– MONTGOMERY: 我同样辞职。
– PRESTON:他被开除了
– MONTGOMERY: I agreed to resign.
– PRESTON: He was pushed out
为了安抚那些讨厌的激进党派！
to placate the goddamn
radical abolishonists!
ELIZABETH:噢　爸爸，请！
爸爸。
ELIZABETH: Oh Daddy, please!
Daddy.
哦，你不介意，小子，你呢？
Oh. You don’t mind, boy, do you?
他把他的时间都花在士兵身上了。
He spends his days with soldiers.
－他们教论文我一首歌！
－他们是？
– They taught me a song!
– Did they?
PRESTON: 士兵知道各种各样的歌曲。
PRESTON: Soldiers know
all manner of songs.
PRESTON: ：你的哥哥Bob怎么样？
PRESTON: How’s your brother Bob?
他现在在学校，不过他会在这４天内过来。
He’s at school now, but he’s coming
to visit in four days. For the shindy!
PRESTON:在学校？不是很好吗！
PRESTON: t school? Ain’t that fine!
不错，他不在军队里面！
Good he’s not in the army!
TAD: 他想去军队，但是妈妈不让．．．
TAD: He wants to be,
but mama said he can’t...
很危险，士兵们的生活。
Dangerous life, soldiering.
你妈妈是明智的，别让他去那里。
Your mama is wise to
keep him clean out of that.
现在．．．你爸爸知道我想要什么，作为我给他帮助的回报，
Now... your daddy knows that what I want,
in return for all the help I give him,
延续到 Richmond，就像他说我做的，直到Savannah，
is to go down to Richmond like he said
I could, as soon as Savannah fell,
和杰弗森　戴维斯谈话。
and talk to Jefferson Davis.
PRESTON: 就我而言，我可以提供给杰弗森　戴维斯
PRESTON: Give me terms I can
offer to Jefferson Davis
去开始和平交涉，
他将和我对话！
to start negotiating for peace,
he’ll talk to me!
你们党派的保守份子
Conservative members of your party
希望你听从来自 Richmond的和平建议。
以上所有！！
want you to listen to overtures
from Richmond. That above all!
他们将投票给这个激进和危险的修正案
They’ll vote for this rash
and dangerous amendment
只有当所有其他的可能都失败。
only if every other
possibility is exhausted.
我们共和党人不是废奴主义者。
Our Republicans ain’t abolitionists.
我们不能告诉我们的人民，他们将赞成我们
We can’t tell our people they can vote yes
废除奴隶制度，直到我们可以告诉他们的时候
on abolishing slavery unless
at the same time we can tell ‘em
你正在寻求通过谈判实现和平。
that you’re seeking a negotiated peace.
ELIZABETH: Leo, 还有一百英里到Richmond.
ELIZABETH: Leo, it’s a
hundred miles to Richmond.
让他喝点，这样他就能睡觉了。
－好的，夫人。
Get him drunk so he can sleep.
– Yes ma'am.
这里，爸爸。
Here, daddy.
－喔，谢谢。
－让我们来解决它．．．
– Oh. Thank you.
– Let’s fix this up...
－我的帽子在哪？
－Leo 拿着您的帽子。
– Where’s my hat?
– Leo has your hat.
准备好了吗？
去议和。
All right?
Go make peace.
Thunder forth, God of War!
STANTON: 我们将在从海边想向Wilmington发动攻击。
STANTON: We’ll commence our
assault on Wilmington from the sea.
为什么会受伤的？
Why is this burnt?
是和这男孩造成的吗？
Was the boy playing with it?
林肯：几个晚上功夫就轻松得到它
LINCOLN: It got took by
breeze several nights back.
这是一张正式的美国陆军部的地图！
This is an official War Department map!
所有的内阁正在等着听这预示着什么
SEWARD: And the entire cabinet’s
waiting to hear what it portends.
一个轰炸
WELLES: A bombardment.
最大的海军舰队已经集结好了
From the largest fleet
the Navy has ever assembled.
旧海王星，摇动你的陈旧的头发吧！
LINCOLN: Old Neptune,
shake thy hoary locks!
58艘船正在进行中，包括吨位跟射程
WELLES: Fifty-eight ships are underway,
of every tonnage and firing range.
我们要保正火力
STANTON: We’ll keep up a steady barrage.
我们的第一个目标是费舍尔城堡
Our first target is Fort Fisher.
我坚守Wilmington港口
It defends Wilmington Port.
稳定的火力
JAMES SPEED: A steady barrage?
每分钟一百发炮弹
A hundred shells a minute.
知道他们投降
Till they surrender.
亲爱的上帝啊
– WILLIAM FESSENDEN: Dear God.
对，对
– WELLES: Yes, yes.
Wilmington是他们最后的海港了。然后...
LINCOLN: Wilmington’s their
last open seaport. Therefore...
Wilmington失陷，然后就是Richmond了
STANTON: Wilmington falls,
Richmond falls after.
然后战争就会结束
SEWARD: And the war is done.
这就是为什么我可能问的
JOHN USHER: Then why, if I may ask,
我们会把国家的注意力集中在Wilmington？
are we not concentrating
the nation’s attention on Wilmington?
为什么，等等，这就是预示吗？
Why, instead, are we
reading in the Herald,
反对奴隶制的修正法案会沉淀
that the anti-slavery amendment
is being precipitated
在议会的讨论上
onto the House floor for debate?
因为你的热切，未经授权的执行官闯入
Because your eagerness, in what seems
an unwarranted intrusion of the Executive
立法庭里是很能说明问题的对那个...
into Legislative prerogatives,
is compelling it to it’s...
导致过早的总结
to what’s likely to be
its premature demise.
你听？
You hear?
你制定的解放宣言，你做了
You signed the Emancipation
Proclamation, you’ve done
所有可以看到的。
all that can be expected.
解放宣言只
– The Emancipation Proclamation’s
不过是战争措施。
merely a war measure.
战争之后法院会给出评定
After the war the courts will make
当Edward Bates
a meal of it.
– When Edward Bates
首席检查官的时候
was Attorney General,
他有足够的信心允许你签字
he felt confident in it enough
to allow you to sign.
不同的律师有不同的想法
– Different lawyers, different opinions.
自由的奴隶是一种军事需求，不是在其他方面
It frees slaves as a military
exigent, not in any other...
我不想打电话给Edward Bates去
LINCOLN: I don’t recall Edward
Bates being any too certain
重申我的宣告的合法性
about the legality of my Proclamation...
那不是彻底的罪犯
just it wasn’t downright criminal.
他们中间的某处
Somewhere’s in between.
当我在伊利诺斯州法定的道路上骑车的时候回来了
Back when I rode the legal
circuit in Illinois,
我保卫了一名77岁并自己取名叫Melissa Goings的老妇人
I defended a woman from Metamora named
Melissa Goings的老妇人
Melissa Goings, 77 years old.
他们说她杀了她83岁的丈夫
They said she murdered
her husband, he was 83.
他当时正在掐她，34，她
He was choking her, and, uh, she
抓起一根木材棒然后
grabbed a hold of a stick of fire wood and
敲碎了他的脑壳，他死了
fractured his skull, ‘n he died.
在他的想法里他写着：
In his will he wrote:
我预料到她会杀了我
“I expect she has killed me.
如果我挺过去，我会复仇的
If I get over it, I will have revenge.
没有人尖锐的指着她的罪行
No one was keen to see her convicted,
他是一个好丈夫
he was that kind of husband.
我问检察官是否我可以跟我的委托人讨论一下
I asked the prosecuting attorney
if I might have a short conference
她和我走进法院大楼的密室
with my client.
And she and I
但是只有我自己出来了
went into a room in the courthouse,
but I alone emerged.
房间的窗户大开着
The window in the room
was found to be wide open,
相信一个老女人可能爬出去
It was believed the old lady
may have climbed out of it.
我通知了法警
I told the bailiff...
在我留下她在房间里离开前
Right before I left her in the room,
她问我哪里可以喝些好的东西
she asked me where she could get
a good drink of water,
我告诉她在田纳西州有
and I told her Tennessee.
Goings太太看起来在Metamora已经一无所有了
Mrs. Goings was seen no more in Metamora.
正义履行了
Enough justice had been done.
他们甚至返还了他的养老金
They even forgave the bondsman her bail.
我恐怕看不到...
– JOHN USHER: I’m afraid I don’t see...
我了解
– LINCOLN: I decided
宪法给了我战争的权利
that the Constitution gives me war powers,
但是没人知道确切的权利到底是什么
but no one knows just exactly
what those powers are.
有些人说他们不存在
Some say they don’t exist.
我不知道。我坚信
I don’t know. I decided,
我需要他们出来支持我的宣告来保护宪法
I needed them to exist to uphold
my oath to protect the Constitution,
我确定我可以解决那些在战争中财产
which I decided meant that I could
take the rebels’ slaves from ‘em as
别没收的反叛的奴隶们
property confiscated in war.
那可能交付
That might recommend to suspicion
that I agree with the rebs
那些南军士兵奴隶在第一区里财产
that their slaves are property in
我当然不这么认为
the first place. Of course I don’t.
我从来没有。我很高兴看到人们自由。而且如果没收财产
I never have, I’m glad to see any man
free, and if calling a man property, or
或者战争走私，
war contraband, does the trick,
为什么我抓住的机会，获得了成功
why I caught at the opportunity.
现在这是真正的自由了
Now here’s where it gets truly slippery.
我利用法律去扣押战争中的财产
I use the law allowing for
the seizure of property
以便于用用在政府的财政上
in a war knowing it applies only to
the property of governments and
跟国家战争后的重建上
citizens of belligerent nations.
但是南方不是国家的
But the South ain’t a nation.
那就是为什么我不可以跟南军士兵交涉
That’s why I can’t negotiate with ’em.
所以如果实际上黑人遵循对财产立的法律
So if in fact the Negroes are
property according to law,
我有权没收反叛者的财产吗？
have I the right to take the
rebels’ property from ‘em,
在我坚持他们只是造反不是交战区的公民的时候
if I insist they’re rebels only,
and not citizens of a belligerent country?
And slipperier still: I maintain it ain’t
our actual Southern states in rebellion,
但是只有叛军住在这个州的时候
but only the rebels
living in those states,
法律仍然有效
the laws of which states remain in force.
The laws of which states remain in force.
那意味着，那个州的法律决定
That means, that since it’s
states’ laws that determine
是否黑人可以当作是一种奴隶有事财产来贩卖
whether Negroes can be sold
as slaves, as property,
联邦政府没有讨论这些
the Federal government
doesn’t have a say in that,
至少现在还没有
at least not yet,
那么这些州的黑人就是奴隶，但也是财产
then Negroes in those states
are slaves, hence property, hence
我的作战权利允许我去没收
my war powers allow me to confiscate‘em
所以我就没收
as such, so I confiscated ‘em.
但是如果我是州法律的制定者
LINCOLN:(CONT’D): But if
I’m a respecter of states’ laws,
那么我有什么资格声明法律上的自由
how then can I legally free‘em
with my Proclamation as I done,
至少我取消州法律？
unless I’m cancelling states’ laws?
我发现战争需要这些
I felt the war demanded it.
我的宣言需要这些
my oath demanded it,
我感觉我是对的，我希望这是合法的
I felt right with myself, and I
hoped it was legal to do it
我现在仍然这么希望
I’m hoping still.
两年后，我正式宣布这些人自由了
Two years ago I proclaimed
these people emancipated,
从那时起到永远自由了
" then, thenceforward and forever free.”
但是法院声明我没有权利决定这些
But let’s say the courts decide
I had no authority to do it.
他们可能会更好的判定
They might well decide that.
声明那里没有修改废除奴隶制
Say there’s no amendment
abolishing slavery.
声明战争之后废除
Say it’s after the war,
我可能不会再动用我发动战争的权利去反对法院的判决
and I can no longer use my war powers
to just ignore the courts’ decisions,
就像有事我感觉我必须去做
like I sometimes felt I had to do,
这些我从奴隶制中释放出来的人可能别安排好？
Might those people I freed
be ordered back into slavery?
那就是为什么我想从白宫中拿到第十三修正法案
That’s why I’d like to get the Thirteenth
Amendment through the House,
以这种方式被许可
and on its way to ratification
by the states,
结合整件奴隶制这件事
wrap the whole slavery thing up,
我会永远的坚持下去
forever and aye, as soon as I’m able,
现在！这个 月末！
Now! End of this month!
我想你站在我后面
And I’d like you to stand behind me,
作为我的内阁议员永远做下去
like my cabinet’s most always done.
当传教士说，我可以写一篇更短的说教但是
As the preacher said, I could
write shorter sermons but
一旦我开始，然后又因为太懒停止了。
once I start I get too lazy to stop.
JOHN USHER: 在我看来，先生，
您描述的非常准确。
JOHN USHER: It seems to me,
sir, you’re describing precisely
那些独裁者就知道在那里嚎叫。
the sort of dictator the Democrats
have been howling about.
JAMES SPEED:独裁者不容易受到法律的影响。
JAMES SPEED: Dictators
aren’t susceptible to law.
USHER: 也不是他！
他只是说了不少！
USHER: Neither is he!
He just said as much!
不顾法庭，扭曲事实，等等...
Ignoring the courts,
twisting meanings, what...
什么控制他从，从...
-好吧，
what reins him in from, from...
– Well,
人民会做那个的，我想。
the people do that, I suppose.
我签署独立宣言已经一年半了，
I signed the Emancipation
Proclamation a year and half,
在我第二次当选前，
before my second election,
我想在我的能力范围之内去做它。
I felt I was within my power to do it.
不过我经常感觉我可能做错了。
However I also felt that I might be
wrong about that.
我知道人民会告诉我，
I knew the people would tell me,
我给了他们一年半去考虑它，他们又再次选择我。
I gave ‘em a year and half to think
about it, and they reelected me.
到了2月份首先，我要签署第13号修正案。
And come February the first,
I intend to sign the Thirteenth Amendment.
LINCOLN: 好吧，Mr. Representative Ashley
LINCOLN: Well, Mr. Representative Ashley!
告诉我们从Hill来的消息。
Tell us the news from the Hill.
– JAMES ASHLEY: 嗯，好的，消息...
–例如为什么是这样，因此,
– JAMES ASHLEY: Ah! Well, news...
– Why for instance is this thus,
为什么是这样的原因？
and what is the reason for this thusness?
James, 我们希望你把反奴隶制度修正案拿出来讨论。
James, we want you to bring the anti-
slavery amendment to the floor for debate.
-抱歉，什么？
-马上。
– Excuse me, what?
– Immediately.
你的这个修正案的管理人，不是吗？
You are the amendment’s manager,
are you not?
我是，当然，但是...
I am, of course, but...
我们希望强大的激进派能够支持，所有告诉Mr. Stevens
And we’re counting on robust
radical support, so tell Mr. Stevens
我们期望他能够竭尽全力，
这不是一个容易的事情，
we expect him to put his back into it.
It’s not going to be easy,
但是我们相信...
-这是不可能的。
but we trust...
– It’s impossible.
不，我很抱歉，不，我们不能在这里立即组织任何事情。
No, I am sorry, no, we can’t organize
anything immediately in the House.
自从选举以后，我一直在游说民主党，
I have been canvassing the
Democrats since the election,
在他们遭到打击后，以防其中任何一个被软化。但是
in case any of them softened
after they got walloped. But
他们变得更加强硬，秘书先生，
they have stiffened if anything,
Mr. Secretary,
没有足够的选票...
-林肯：我们是捕鲸者，Mr. Ashley!
there aren’t nearly enough votes...
– LINCOLN: We’re whalers, Mr. Ashley!
捕鲸者？那么，嗯...鲸鱼？
Whalers? As in, um... whales?
LINCOLN:我们追逐这条鲸鱼很长一段时间了。
LINCOLN: We’ve been chasing
this whale for a long time.
我们终于把鱼叉叉在怪物的背上了。
We’ve finally placed a harpoon
in the monster’s back.
就是这样，James，就是这样！
It’s in, James, it’s in!
我们现在就要结束行动，我们不能等了！
We finish the deed now, we can’t wait!
否则会留一个失败的尾巴，
Or with one flop of his tail,
他将粉碎这条船，并给我们所有人永恒。
he’ll smash the boat
and send us all to eternity.
SEWARD: 在今年，这个月的31号。
SEWARD: On the 31st
of this month. Of this year.
将这个修正案进行表决。
Put the amendment up for a vote.
BLUFF WADE:捕鲸者？
BLUFF WADE: Whalers?
ASHLEY: 这是他说的。
ASHLEY: That’s what he said.
这个男人一生中从来没有靠近过捕鲸船！
The man’s never been near
a whale ship in his life!
撤回激进派的支持，
Withdraw radical support,
迫使他放弃这个计划，
无论他怎么样。
force him to abandon this scheme,
whatever he’s up to.
他-他...他拖延他所有的行动，林肯。为什么这么紧迫？
He-He... He drags his feet about
everything, Lincoln. Why this urgency?
我们将它通过了参议院，没有太大的难度，
因为我们有数量上的优势。
We got it through the Senate without
difficulty because we had the numbers.
到了12月份，你将在议员做同样的事情。
Come December you’ll have
the same in the House.
修正案将在10分钟内简单的执行。
The amendment’ll be the
easy work of ten minutes.
ASA VINTNER LITTON:他将用修正案的威胁
ASA VINTNER LITTON: He’s using
the threat of the amendment
去迫使反政府立即投降。
to frighten the rebels
into an immediate surrender.
SCHUYLER COLFAX: 我想我们会很高兴看到这些。
SCHUYLER COLFAX: I imagine
we’d rejoice to see that.
你会庆幸，当南部重新返回这个杂乱的联盟就像
Will you rejoice, when the Southern states
have re-joined the Union pell-mell as
林肯打算的那样，一个接一个的拒绝签署修正案？
Lincoln intends them to, and one by one
each refuses to ratify the amendment?
如果我们通过它，我们将不.
If we pass it, which we won’t.
为什么我们...不和他进行联合呢？
Why are we... co-operating with-with him?
我们都知道他在做什么，
并且我们都知道他将做什么。
We all know what he’s doing,
and we all know what he’ll do.
我们不能提供废奴制度的最好方法，是去祈祷他的游戏和诡计。
We can’t offer up abolition’s best
legal prayer to his games and tricks.
他说他欢迎南方和它所有被囚禁的奴隶回来。
He’s said he’d welcome the South
back with all its slaves in chains.
三年前，他说这些。
为了平息边境。
Three years ago he said that.
To calm the border states
当我们...
--VOICE: 我不会。
when we were...
– VOICE: I don't.
THADDEUS STEVENS: 你说的
“我们都知道他将做什么”  我不知道。
THADDEUS STEVENS: You said
“we all know what he’ll do.” I don’t know.
– LITTON:你知道他不可信任。
–信任？喔...
– LITTON: You know he isn’t to be trusted.
– Trust? Oh...
我很抱歉，我是在误解你的所选择的职业是政治了。
I’m sorry, I was under the misapprehension
your chosen profession was politics.
我从来没有相信过总统。
我从来不相信任何人。
I’ve never trusted the President.
I never trust anyone.
但是，他不感到惊讶吗?
But hasn’t he surprised you?
LITTON: 没， Mr. Stevens,他没有。
LITTON: No, Mr. Stevens, he hasn’t.
没有人对你惊讶，Asa。
Nothing surprises you, Asa.
因此没有人对你表示惊讶。
Therefore nothing about
you is surprising.
也许这就是为什么你的选民没有重新选择你的原因。
Perhaps that is why your constituents
did not re-elect you to the coming term.
太迟了，我老了，我要回家了。
It’s late, I’m old, I’m going home.
STEVENS (CONT’D): 林肯这个游手好闲的懒人，林肯这个南方人，
STEVENS (CONT’D): Lincoln the inveterate
dawdler, Lincoln the Southerner,
林肯这个投降主义者，
Lincoln the capitulating compromiser,
我们的...敌人和...
our... adversary and....
被神抛弃的领导者
共和党，我们的党派。
leader of the god forsaken
Republican Party, our party.
亚伯拉罕·林肯让我们和他一起工作
Abraham Lincoln has
asked us to work with him
在美国去实现奴隶制度的废除。
to accomplish the death
of slavery in America.
保留，甚至反对，
Retain, even in opposition,
你的能力令人惊讶。
your capacity for astonishment.
总统从来没有提起过。
The President is never to be mentioned.
我也没有。你要付出你的判断力。
Nor I. You’re paid for your discretion.
W.N. BILBO: Hell,你能做什么，我们需要的是钱去贿赂。
W.N. BILBO: Hell, you can have that for
nothin’, what we need money for is bribes.
它会加快速度。
It’d speed things up.
SEWARD: 不.没有什么是绝对的违法的。
SEWARD: No. Nothing strictly illegal.
ROBERT LATHAM: 贿赂国会议员不是非法的。否则他们会挨饿。
ROBERT LATHAM: It’s not illegal to bribe
Congressmen. They starve otherwise.
我已经向Mr. Bilbo 和 Mr. Latham解释过
I have explained to
Mr. Bilbo and Mr. Latham
我们会提供工作给民主党中投票的人。
that we’re offering patronage
jobs to the Dems who vote yes.
工作而已。
– SEWARD: 这是正确的。
Jobs and nothing more.
– SEWARD: That’s correct.
BILBO:国会议员更便宜！
几千Buck可以买到所有你想要的。
BILBO: Congressmen come cheap!
Few thousand bucks’ll buy you all you need.
总统会不高兴听到你这样做。
The President would be unhappy
to hear you did that.
好了，他会不高兴，如果我们输了？
Well, will he be unhappy if we lose?
钱可以让我去提高这一努力
The money I managed to
raise for this endeavor
这是只给你的费用，你的食物，和住宿，先生。
is only for your fees, your
food, and lodgings, sir.
嗯。
Uh huh.
如果我们住在松鼠，害虫出没的，没有任何措施的阁楼里面，
If that squirrel-infested attic you’ve
quartered us in’s any measure,
你没有筹集了太多。
you ain’t raised much.
我们可以去工作了吗？
Shall we get to work?
[Gavel slams down]
COLFAX: 议院承认Fernando Wood有效，
COLFAX: The House
recognizes Fernando Wood,
[Democrats applaud]
这是从纽约来的代表。
the honorable representative
from New York.
FERNANDO WOOD:难得可贵的同事。
FERNANDO WOOD: Estimable colleagues.
两年前那些流血的岁月，
Two bloody years ago this month,
尊敬的亚伯拉罕殿下
黑人们第一次，
his Highness King Abraham
Africanus the First,
我们伟大的篡夺者凯撒，
our Great Usurping Caesar,
违反人身保护权和言论自由，
violator of habeas corpus
and freedom of the press,
滥用国家权力...
abuser of states’ rights...
HIRAM PRICE:如果林肯真的是一个暴君， Mr. Wood
HIRAM PRICE: If Lincoln really
were a tyrant, Mr. Wood,
他将会把你空空的脑袋钉在架子上！
he’d’a had your empty head
impaled on a pike!
国家会变的更好！
And the country better for it!
你的激进独裁分子.
Your radical republican autocrat
是政策是军法规定的。
ruling by fiat and martial law,
把他的名字贴在那个可恶而且非法的解放公告上吧。
affixed his name to his on a heinous
and illicit Emancipation Proclamation,
保证它可以赶快结束战争。
promising it would hasten
the end of the war,
哪个还没流行起来。
which yet rages on and on.
WOOD（续）：他声称，作为一个暴君所为，
WOOD (CONT’D): He claimed, as tyrants do,
战争的突发事件允许他调转我们的军队...
that the war’s emergencies
permitted him to turn our army...
LATHAM：纽约
代表团的观测肯定是缺乏灵感的。
LATHAM: The New York
delegation’s looking decidedly uninspired.
..激进分子的共和废奴主义狂热了！
.. and radical Republicanism’s
abolitionist fanaticism!
[长啸，来自共和党的嘘声]
[Shouts and boos from Republicans]
WOOD（续）：他的解放黑奴宣言抹杀了数百万美元...
WOOD (CONT'D): His Emancipation Proclamation
has obliterated millions of dollars...
理查德·谢尔：在宾夕法尼亚州的...
满身是汗的人吃了他的拇指是谁？
RICHARD SCHELL: Over in Pennsylvania...
who’s the sweaty man eating his thumb?
LATHAM：我不清楚。似乎很纠结。
LATHAM: Unknown to me.
Seems jumpy.
也许他会跳。
Perhaps he’ll jump.
但是，所有这些对独裁者是不够的，
But all that was not
enough for this dictator,
现在谁会去暗指什么...
who now seeks to insinuate...
毕尔博：耶稣！
BILBO: Jesus!
何时那狗娘养的会下去？
When’s this son-of liberty
sonofabitch gonna sit down?
SCHELL：约翰·埃利斯会打破他的手表，如果他不停止。
SCHELL: John Ellis is going to
break his watch if he doesn’t stop.
WOOD（续）：我们再次要求...
WOOD (CONT’D): We are once again asked...
不仅如此，命令去考虑
下提出来的第十三条修正。
nay, commanded to consider a
proposed thirteenth amendment.
其中，如果通过，
可以直接就自由咯？
Which, if passed, shall
set at immediate liberty
4000000有色人种，而切断美国白色人种中的分支
four million coloreds while manacling
the limbs of the white race in America
如果是通过。
但不应该通过！
If it is passed.
But it shall not pass!
更有趣的是惨淡而且满腹牢骚的耶曼先生如何出现。
What’s more interesting is how dismal
and disgruntled Mr. Yeaman appears.
WOOD（续）：这所房子的每个成员......
WOOD (CONT’D): Every
member of this House....
LATHAM：他现在应该
欢呼，但...
LATHAM: He should be
cheering right now, but...
W.N. BILBO：看起来像他吃了坏的牡蛎。
W.N. BILBO: Looks like
he ate a bad oyster.
WOOD（续）：它服务的那些选民应该反对!
WOOD (CONT’D): .. and the constituents
which it serves shall oppose!
STEVENS：命令的要点是，议长先生，如果你愿意？
STEVENS: A point of order,
Mr. Speaker, if you please?
议长先生，我仍然有基底的。
Mr. Speaker, I still have the floor,
来自宾夕法尼亚州的绅士
and the gentleman from Pennsylvania
是乱来！
- 史蒂文斯：何时Wood先生会
is out of order!
– STEVENS: When will Mr. Wood
结束他没完没了地胡扯？
conclude his interminable gabble?
我们中的一些人呼吸氧气，
Some of us breathe oxygen,
我们在他的演说中找到了一些猫腻。
and we find the mephitic
fumes of his oratory
对我们的肺容量来说是一个致命的挑战。
a lethal challenge to
our pulmonary capacities.
WOOD:我们会反对这个修正案，
WOOD: We shall oppose this amendment,
有什么法律是如此侮辱自然法规的,
and any legislation that
so affronts natural law,
作为凡人去侮辱上帝！
insulting to God as to man!
国会绝不会向那些上帝创造出来的不平等提出平等。
Congress must never declare equal
those whom God created unequal!
STEVENS：奴隶制是唯一的侮辱
自然法则的，你这个二货！
STEVENS: Slavery is the only insult
to natural law, you fatuous nincompoop!
乔治·潘德尔顿（大喊）：
这是命令。
GEORGE PENDLETON (SHOUTING):
ORDEEER!
程序！议长先生，
Wood先生有了不少底基。
Procedure! Mr. Speaker,
Mr. Wood has the floor!
指导我们，伟大的平民哦，
什么是不自然的，在您看来？
Instruct us, Oh Great Commoner,
what is unnatural, in your opinion?
Niggrahs投票？
Niggrahs casting ballots?
Niggrah代表，
是自然的好吧，史蒂文斯？
Niggrah representatives,
is that natural, Stevens?
近亲通婚吗？
Intermarriage?
STEVENS：违反自然法则，奴役，
STEVENS: What violates natural law, slavery，
彭德尔顿，你，你侮辱上帝！
and you, Pendleton, you insult God!
你就胡扯吧。
You unnatural noise.
[铺天盖地的嘘声和欢呼声]
[Avalanche of boos and cheers]
JAMES ASHLEY：Coffax先生，
请使用您的木槌。
JAMES ASHLEY: Mr. Coffax,
please, use your gavel.
- 希礼：你滚吧！
- COFFAX：这是会议厅！
– ASHLEY: You are out of order!
– COFFAX: Order in the Chamber!
ASHLEY：让中士来压制一下！
ASHLEY: Instruct the sergeant
of arms to suppress this!
希礼：我们是在开会！
ASHLEY: We are in session!
TOM PENDEL：请不要扇阴风点鬼火！
TOM PENDEL: Please don’t encourage this!
不要乱来！
Don’t encourage this!
TAD：你回来了，你回来了，
你回来了，你回来了！
TAD: You’re back, you’re back,
you’re back, you’re back!
我是。
你的山羊了变大了哦。
I am.
Your goat got big.
在这里，帮我把这些拿出去。
Here, help me get one
of these to my room.
她在那里吗？
Is she in there?
她可能睡着了吧。
TAD: She’s asleep, probably.
需要帮助吗先生？我可以..
不用了，不要。
– You need help, sir? I can...
– No, sir, I don’t. No.
- 请求人：我可以......
- 罗伯特：滚球。
– PETITIONER: I can...
– ROBERT: No.
你能把这封破产声明的信拿给你的爸爸吗？
Could you bring your pa this letter
I writ about my insolvency proceedings?
罗伯特：你自己发你那该死的请愿书去...
ROBERT: You deliver your
own goddamned petition...
TAD：。 “因为有一本新书，
山姆贝克威思说的是关于雀鸟的，
TAD: .. ‘cause there’s a new book that
Sam Beckwith says is about finches,
雀的喙，他们如何...
and finches’ beaks, about how they...
他在这里，夫人伯特！
他在这里！
He’s here, Mrs. Cuthbert!
He’s here!
- 罗比...
- 嗨，妈妈。
– Robbie...
– Hi, ma.
- 哦，罗比...
- 嘿。
– Oh, Robbie...
– Hey.
罗比。哦！
Robbie. Oh!
MARY：什么...？
MARY: What...?
你只去几天而已。
干嘛要收拾所有的包裹？
You’re only staying a few days.
Why’d you pack all of that?
好了，我还不知道我得去多久...
Well, I don’t know how long I’m...
去告诉你父亲罗伯特家人！
Go tell your father Robert’s home!
尼古拉先生说爸爸会和布莱尔先生隐蔽起来。
Mr. Nicolay says daddy’s
secluded with Mr. Blair.
反正告诉他。
Tell him anyway.
- 你忘了吃饭，完全像他。
- 第..
– You forget to eat, exactly like him.
– No...
在接收通知之后，在你回学校前，你会在多呆上几天。
You’ll linger a few days extra, after the
reception, before you go back to school.
嗯，我不知道我是否会回去 ...
Well, I don’t know if I’m
gonna go back to s...
我们会把你养的白白胖胖的在你回去之前。
We’ll fatten you up before
you return to Boston.
- 好吧，妈妈。
- 好呗。
– All right, mama.
– All right.
哦，罗比...
Oh Robbie...
PRESTON布莱尔：杰弗逊·戴维斯
派遣了三名代表：
PRESTON BLAIR: Jefferson Davis
is sending three delegates:
斯蒂芬斯，亨特和坎贝尔。
Stephens, Hunter and Campbell.
南部邦联的副总裁，
他们的前国务卿，
Vice President of the Confederacy,
their former Secretary of State,
和他们的战争助理国务卿。
and their Assistant Secretary of War.
他们在认真提出和平。
They’re coming in earnest
to propose peace.
我知道这个消息对你不好。
I know this is unwelcome news for you.
现在听我说。
Now hear me.
我去里士满和叛徒谈谈，
I went to Richmond to talk to traitors,
以微笑，并恳求叛徒，
to smile at and plead with traitors,
因为两个月内是春天，
because it’ll be spring in two months,
那个将是是差强人意的，
春节大屠杀开始啦
the roads’ll be passable,
the Spring slaughter commences.
四血腥泉！
Four bloody Springs now!
想想我的弗兰克，
到底谁住在你心里的说，
Think of my Frank,
who you’ve taken to your heart,
你会责怪自己的，如果战争把我的儿子带走了
how you’ll blame yourself
if the war takes my son
它也带走了许多的儿子。
as it’s taken multitudes of sons.
想想所有的男孩，谁会死
如果你没有实现和平。
Think of all the boys who’ll die
if you don’t make peace.
你必须跟这些人谈谈！
You must talk with these men!
正有此意，普雷斯顿。
I intend to, Preston.
而作为回报，我必须问你...
- 不，这不是房屋贸易好吧，
And in return, I must ask you...
– No, this is not horsetrading,
这就是生活！
- 林肯：不是现在！
this is life!
– LINCOLN: NOT NOW!
林肯：鲍勃。对不起。
LINCOLN: Bob. I’m sorry.
林肯：欢迎你回家。
- 罗伯特：谢谢你。
LINCOLN: Welcome home.
– ROBERT: Thank you.
您正在寻找合适的啥，罗伯特。
哈佛同意与你一起。
You’re looking fit, Robert.
Harvard agrees with you.
- 布莱尔先生。
- 普雷斯顿的儿子。
–  Mr. Blair.
– Preston, son.
林肯：你可以离开一下吗？，罗伯特。谢谢。
LINCOLN: If you just give us
a moment please, Robert. Thank you.
我将会遵守我对您的承诺，为您取得更多的赞成票
I will procure your votes for you,
as I promised, sir.
你对我总是说话算是
You’ve always kept your word to me.
那些南方人来了
Those Southern men are coming.
祈求伟大的救世主阿
I beg you, in the name
of Gentle Christ, sir.
我明白
LINCOLN: I understand.
和他们探讨一下和平
Talk peace with these men.
我会的，Preston
I understand, Preston.
迄今为止我们有一个弃权票
LATHAM: We have
one abstention so far.
SCHELL: Jacob Graylor.
评审员宾夕法尼亚的第五区。
SHELL: He’d like to be Federal Revenue
Assessor for the Fifth District of Pennsylvania.
所以三周后众议院的总投票人数减少为182人
LATHAM: So the total of representatives voting
three weeks from today is reduced to 182,
也就是说我们需要122票赞成票来达到众议院的三分之二通过线
which means 122 yes votes to reach
the requisite two thirds of the House.
假设所有的共和党人都投赞成票
Assuming all Republicans
vote for the amendment.
然后，除去有人缺席的
Then, despite our abstention,
要达到三分之二也还差20票赞成票
to reach a two-thirds majority
we remain 20 yeses short.
我们就要从64个废柴民主党议员里面找出这20来了
LATHAM (CONT'D): For which we’re seeking
from among 64 lame duck Democrats.
其中39个我们认为肯定会投否定票
Fully 39 of these we deem
unredeemable no votes.
他们讨厌黑人
BILBO: The kind that hates niggers,
憎恨上帝创造出黑人
hates God for making niggers.
上帝也会对他们的灵魂绝望的
LATHAM: The Good Lord on High
would despair of their souls.
谢谢你简短的阐释，Mr. Bilbo
SEWARD: Thank you for that
pithy explanation, Mr. Bilbo.
我们已经放弃了这39个被魔鬼迷了心窍的人了
SCHELL: We’ve abandoned these 39
to the Devil that possesses them.
剩下的人，我们就是有目的地进行工作了
SCHELL: The remaining lame ducks,
on whom we’ve been working with a purpose.
Charles Hanson
Charles Hanson.
Giles Stuart.
Nelson Merrick.
Homer Benson.
最后还有...
And lastly...
俄亥俄州的Clay Hawkins
BILBO: Clay Hawkins. Of Ohio.
西储的税务官...
CLAY HAWKINS: T-tax collector
for the Western Reserve, it...
那个待遇很优厚啊
Th-that pays handsomely.
不要只盯着那些最高的部门，其实很多地方都不错
BILBO: Don't just reach for the highest
branches, they sway in every breeze.
马尔斯顿的助理港口督察，我就觉得不错
Assistant Port Inspector of Marlston
looks like the ticket to me.
呃，船，那个那个……我晕船
HAWKINS: Uh, boats,
they-they make me sick.
那就站在码头就行了
So just stand on the dock.
让助理港口督察的助理去反胃呗
Let the Assistant Assistant Port
Inspector’s stomach go weak.
最后一个，第六个民主党的赞成票，俄亥俄州的Hawkins
SEWARD: And lastly, Democratic yes
vote number six. Hawkins from Ohio.
- 六票啊
- 目前为止
– LINCOLN; Six.
– SEWARD: Well, thus far.
还加上格雷勒的缺席
SEWARD: Plus Graylor’s abstention.
- 一点一点来吧
- 霍金斯会得到什么职位？
From tiny acorns and so on.
– LINCOLN: Wha’d Hawkins get?
米勒斯堡邮局局长
NICOLAY: Postmaster of
the Millersburg Post Office.
他给自己的定价还挺便宜啊，是吧？
He’s selling himself cheap, ain’t he?
嗯，他想要当西储的税务官
SEWARD: Aye, he wanted tax
collector of the Western Reserve,
一个处于第一任期的议员，都不能成功连任
a first-term congressman
who couldn’t manage reelection,
我觉得不大体面，所以就跟他最终谈成了邮局局长
I felt it unseemly and they
bargained him down to Postmaster.
把他们过来的时间分开安排，这样就没人注意到了
Scatter ‘em over several rounds
of appointments, so no one notices,
结束之后请把账目烧掉
and burn this ledger,
please, after you’re done.
该洗个舆论澡了
LINCOLN: Time for my public opinion bath.
或许该让他们来了
Might as well let ‘em in.
跟Ellis先生共事七年了，还有13年
LINCOLN: Seven yeses
with Mr. Ellis. Thirteen to go.
最后一件事，有点荒谬，但...
One last item, an absurdity, but...
我的同事报告说在众议院代表中
My associates report that
among the Representatives,
有个很神奇的传言说是关于
a fantastical rumor’s bruited about,
我也马上进行了否认
which I immediately disavowed,
你让老Preston Blair去了一趟里士满
that you’d allowed bleary old
Preston Blair to sojourn to Richmond
让Jeff Davis派专员来华盛顿谈判和解
to invite Jeff Davis to send commissioners
up to Washington with a peace plan.
我当然告诉他们你绝对不会...
I, of course, told them you would never..
不会不问我的意见就...
Not without consulting me, you wouldn’t...
因为你到底为什么会这么做呢？
Because why on earth would you?
ALEXANDER STEPHENS:
Much obliged.
为什么不先问我？我是国务卿！
SEWARD: Why wasn’t I consulted?!
I’m Secretary of State!
你...以非正式的方式派去一个保守派的老头...
You... you-you informally
send a reactionary dottard to...
接下来会怎样，你想过没有，这些谈判官员来了以后？
What will happen, do you imagine,
when these peace commissioners arrive?
- 我们会仔细听取
- 哦，那真好啊！
– We’ll hear ‘em out.
– Oh, splendid!
接下来民主党就会把他们请去国会山的听证会
And next the Democrats will
invite ‘em up to hearings on the Hill,
然后报纸会，啊，报纸啊
and the newspapers,
well, the newspapers
报纸就会问
the newspapers will ask
“为什么冒着激怒同盟的风险提出废除奴隶制
“why risk enraging the Confederacy
over the issue of slavery
与此同时已经有人来和平谈判？”
when they’re here to make peace?”
我们会失去已经得到的所有民主党选票
We’ll lose every Democrat we’ve got,
并且很有可能那些保守派的共和党也会加入他们
more than likely conservative Republicans
will join ‘em, and all our work,
我们所有为了投票的准备工作就都付诸东流了
all our preparing the ground for
the vote, laid waste, for naught.
布莱尔一家已经许诺如果我们听取这些人的谈判，他们会支持这次修正案
The Blairs have promised support for the
amendment if we listen to these people.
哦，布莱尔说了啊，是吗？
Oh, the Blairs promise, do they?
你觉得我们听完这个谈判然后拒绝掉
You think they’ll keep their promise
once we have heard these delegates
他们还会说话算话吗？我们必须这样做
and refused them?
Which we will have to do,
因为他们的提案几乎肯定会说要保留他们的奴隶！
since their proposal most certainly will
be predicated on keeping their slaves!
威廉，民主党那边的选票还有多少把握
What hope for any
Democratic votes, Willum,
如果已经有传言说我拒绝了这次结束战争的机会？
if word gets out that I’ve
refused a chance to end the war?
你觉得消息不会走漏吗？这是华盛顿啊
You think word won’t get out?
In Washington?
这个修正案和联合的和平谈判，二者不可兼得
It’s either the amendment or this
Confederate peace, you cannot have both.
“假若你能预知将来
“If you can look into the seeds of time,
预测这粒种子会发芽而那粒不会，那就请向我直言...”
and say which grain will grow and
which will not, speak then to me...”
噢，灾难，这真是灾难
SEWARD: Oh, disaster.
This is a disaster!
时间是很好的抚慰，Willum
LINCOLN: Time is a great
thickener of things, Willum.
我猜也是
Yes, I suppose it is.
其实我没听懂你刚才什么意思
Actually I have no idea
what you mean by that.
给我再找13张选票
Get me thirteen votes.
里士满的人现在还没到
Them fellers from Richmond ain’t here yit.
半数的波士顿男人都参军了！
ROBERT: You drafted
half the men in Boston!
你觉得他们的家人会怎么看我？
What do you think their
families think about me?
他们唯一没有朝我扔东西吐痰的原因是
The only reason they don’t
throw things and spit on me
是因为你太有名了
is ‘cause you’re so popular.
我无法专心学习英国重商主义法律
I can’t concentrate on-on
British mercantile law,
我也对英国重商主义法律没兴趣
I don’t care about British mercantile law.
我甚至可能都不想当律师
I might not even want to be a lawyer.
这会是铁饭碗
It’s a sturdy profession,
也会很有用
and a useful one.
是，我想成为有用的人，但是要现在，不是以后！
Yes, and I want to be useful,
but now, not afterwards!
我不想穿这些，Slade先生，从来都不合身
I ain’t wearing them things,
Mr. Slade, they never fit right.
夫人会让您穿的，别想着不穿的事了
The missus will have you wear ‘em.
Don’t think about leaving ‘em.
你又在拖延了，你最喜欢的策略
You’re delaying,
that’s your favorite tactic.
你不会告诉我不许，但战争一个月之内就要结束了，你知道会结束的！
You won’t tell me no, but the war will be
over in a month, and you know it will!
我发现当预言家是一个相当不好预言的职业
LINCOLN: I’ve found that prophesying is
one of life’s less prophet-able occupations.
为什么有些奴隶比其他的贵？
TAD: Why do some slaves
cost more than others?
如果他们年轻、健康，女性还能生孩子
Ah, if they’re still young and healthy,
if the women can still conceive,
- 就值更多的钱
- 放回盒子里去，你这小坏蛋
- they’ll pay more.
–Put ‘em back in the box, you scoundrel.
我们后天就把它们还给Gardner先生
We’ll return them to Mr. Gardner’s
studio day after next.
小心一点拿
Be careful with‘em, now.
这个皮还是呆在牛身上比较好
These things should’ve stayed on the calf.
TAD: When you were a slave,
Mr. Slade, did they beat you?
TAD: 当你是一个奴隶的时候，
Mr. Slade,他们打你了吗？
SLADE: I was born a free man.
SLADE: 我出生就是一个自由民。
Nobody beat me except
I beat them right back.
没有人能打我除了我打他们。
Mr. Lincoln, could you come with me...
林肯先生，你能跟我来一下吗....
Mrs. Keckley was a slave.
Ask her if she was beaten.
Mrs. Keckley曾经是一个奴隶。
问她是否被殴打。
– TAD: Were you?
– Tad!
– TAD: 是你？
MRS. KEKLEY: I was beaten with a fire
shovel when I was younger than you.
当我还很小的时间，我曾经被一个火铲殴打。
You should go to Mrs. Lincoln.
She’s in Willie’s room.
你应该去找林肯太太。
她正在Willie的房间里面。
ROBERT: She never goes in there.
ROBERT:她从来没有去过那里。
JOHN HAY: The reception line
is already stretching out the door.
JOHN HAY: 招待会已经在门外准备了。
See, I’ll be the only man over
fifteen and under sixty-five
看，我将是唯一一个在15到65之间的男人
in this whole place not in uniform.
在这个地方没有穿制服的。
I’m under fifteen.
我还没有15岁。
MARY: My head hurts so.
MARY: 我的头好痛。
I prayed for death
the night Willie died.
我祈祷今晚 Willie去死。
The headaches are how
I know I didn’t get my wish.
头痛怎么样了
我知道我没有实现我的愿望。
How to endure the long afternoon
that go deep into the night.
怎么去忍受从下午一直到深夜。
LINCOLN: I know.
LINCOLN:我知道。
Trying not to think about him.
How will I manage?
试着不去想他。
我将如何管理？
– Somehow you will.
– Somehow.
– 你将会找到办法。
–怎么办。
MARY: Somehow. Somehow. Somehow...
MARY: 怎么办。怎么办。怎么办...
MARY: Every party, every...
MARY:没一个党派，每一个...
And now...
那么...
Four years more in this
terrible house... reproaching us.
在这个糟糕的地方已经4年多了...责备我们把。
He was a very sick little boy.
他是一个生病的小男孩，
We should’ve cancelled
that reception, shouldn’t we?
我们将推掉欢迎会，不是吗？
– We didn’t know how sick he was.
– I knew, I knew...
-我们不知道他怎么生病了。
-我知道，我知道...
I saw that night he was dying.
我看见那天晚上他快要死了.
Three years ago, the war was going
so badly, and we had to put on a face.
3年前，战争正在进行
非常的糟糕，我们不得不装装样子。
– But I... saw Willie was dying.
– Molly.
-但是我...看见Willie快要死了。
-Molly。
– I saw him.
– Listen.
-我看见他.
-听着。
LINCLON: It’s too hard.
林肯： 这太难了。
LINCOLN: Too hard.
林肯：太难了。
WILLIAM SLADE: She’s just ten
feet yonder. I’d like to keep my job.
WILLIAM SLADE:她离那里只有10英尺远。我想保住我的工作。
MARY: Senator Sumner,
it has been much too long.
MARY: Sumner参议员,
它已经太长了。
CHARLES SUMNER: “Oh, who can
look on that celestial face and..."
CHARLES SUMNER: 喔，谁能看着天空中的脸..."
– And...?
– James Ashley, ma’am,
-然后...?
– James Ashley, 女士，
– we’ve met several times.
– Praise Heavens, praise Heavens,
-我们已经见过好几次了。
-赞美上帝，赞美上帝。
just when I had abandoned
hope of amusement,
就在我已经放弃了希望的时候，
it’s the Chairman of the House Ways
and Means Committee!
这是众议院筹款委员会的主席！
THADDEUS STEVENS:
Mrs. Lincoln.
林肯夫人。
Madame President if you please.
主席夫人，如果你请.
Oh, don’t convene another
subcommittee to investigate me, sir!
哦，别在召集其他的小组委员会来调查我了，先生！
I’m teasing! Smile, Senator Wade.
我开玩笑的！笑一个， Wade参议员。
I believe I am smiling, Mrs. Lincoln.
我想我正在笑，林肯夫人.
STEVENS: As long as your household
accounts are in order, Madame,
STEVENS: 只要你的家庭账户是合法的，女士，
we’ll have no need to investigate them.
我们将不需要去调查他们。
You have always taken such a lively,
你的行为总是这样的有趣的，
even prosecutorial interest
in my household accounts.
甚至对我的家庭账户有起诉的兴趣。
Your household accounts
have always been so interesting.
你的家庭账户总是这样的有趣。
Yes, thank you, it’s true,
是啊 ，谢谢你，这是正确的，
the miracles I have wrought out
我已经找出了一些惊人的事情
of fertilizer bills and cutlery
invoices, but I had to!
化肥票据和餐具发票，但是我不得不！
Four years ago, when the President
and I arrived, this was pure pigsty.
五年前，当总统和我到这里的时候，这里完全就是一个猪圈。
Tobacco stains in the turkey carpets.
烟草污染了这些土耳其地毯。
Mushrooms, green as the moon,
sprouting from the ceilings!
蘑菇，绿的就像是月亮，
从天花板上发芽！
And a pauper’s pittance
allotted for improvements.
仅仅分配了一点穷光蛋的微薄金额来改善它。
As if your committee joined
with all of Washington awaiting,
就好像你们的委员会在华盛顿的办事处一样，
in what you anticipated
would be our comfort in squalor,
在你们预期的，我们将舒适的生活在邋塌的环境里面，
further proof that my husband
and I were prairie primitives,
进一步的证明，我的丈夫和我都是大草原的原始人，
unsuited to the position
to which an error of the people,
我们不适应这个位置，可能对人民造成一些错误，
a flaw in the democratic process,
had elevated us.
在民主进程中的一些瑕疵，我们是可以被原谅的。
The past is the past,
it’s a new year now,
过去的已经过去了，
现在是新的一年了，
and we are all getting along,
or so they tell me.
我们都在一起前进，
或者他们告诉我。
I gather we are working together!
我聚集我们在一起工作！
The White House and the other House,
hatching little plans together.
白宫和一些其他的机构，都将给计划带来一些小小的阴影。
– ROBERT: Mother?
– What?
– ROBERT: 妈妈？
– 什么？
– You’re creating a bottleneck.
– Oh!
-你制造了一个颈瓶。
-噢！
MARY: Oh, I’m detaining you.
MARY: 噢，我要扣留你。
And more importantly,
the people behind you.
更重要的是，
你身后的人。
How the people love my husband,
你知道人民多么的热爱我的丈夫，
they flock to see him by
their thousands on public days!
在公共日，他们成群结队去看望他！
They will never love you
the way they love him.
他们将用从没有爱你的方式去热爱他。
How difficult it must be
for you to know that.
这必须是多么的困难你知道。
And yet how important to remember it.
但是更重要的是去记住他。
Since we have the floor
next in the debate,
自从我们在下一个讨论中得到发言权，
I thought I’d suggest you might...
我想我应该建议你...
temper your contributions so as not
to frighten our conservative friends?
控制你的贡献和脾气，只要别吓到我们哪些保守的朋友？
STEVENS: Ashley insists you’re ensuring
approval by dispensing patronage
STEVENS:Ashley 坚决要求你确保赞同去支持
to otherwise undeserving Democrats.
否则不配民主党。
LINCOLN: I can’t ensure a single damn
thing if you scare the whole House
林肯：我不能确保这个该死的事情即使你恐吓整个议院
with talk of land appropriations,
revolutionary tribunals, punitive...
用土地拨款的讨论，革命特别法院，.....
STEVENS: When the war ends,
I intend to push for
STEVENS: 当战争结束的时候，我就打算去争取
full equality, the Negro vote,
and much more.
完全平等，黑人的表决权，以及一些其他的。
Congress shall mandate the seizure
of every foot of rebel land
国会应该授权查封反叛政府的每一个地方
and every dollar of their property.
和他们财产的每一个硬币。
We’ll use their confiscated
wealth to establish
我们应该使用它们被充公的财产去建立
hundreds of thousands
of free Negro farmers,
成百上千的自由黑人农场，
and at their side soldiers armed to occupy
并对在他们那边的士兵进行武装占领
and transform the heritage of traitors.
并且改造那些叛徒的遗产。
We’ll build up a land down there
我们将在那里建立一个高地
of free men and free women
and free children and freedom.
为了那些自由的男人，女人和孩子们。
The nation needs to know
that we have such plans.
这个国家需要知道我们有这样的计划。
That’s the untempered
version of reconstruction.
这个是这个重建物没有改造的版本。
LINCOLN: It’s not... It’s not
quite exactly what I intend,
林肯：这不是...这不是准确上来说这不是我想要的，
but we shall oppose one
another in the course of time.
当时我们将来随着时间的推移，可能会反对其他的。
Now we’re working together,
and I’m asking you...
现在我们在一起工作，
那么我现在要请求你们....
For patience, I expect.
能够坚持，我期望。
LINCOLN: When the people disagree,
bringing them together requires
林肯：当民众不同意的时候，
把他们按照要求整合在一起
going slow till they’re ready to make up.
减慢速度知道他们准备好。
Ah, shit on the people,
噢，该死的民众，
and what they want,
and what they’re ready for,
他们想要什么，
他们到底准备做什么，
I don’t give a goddamn about
the people and what they want!
我根本不在乎这些民众，和他们想要的东西！
This is the face of someone
who has fought long and hard
这就是一些人面对长期和艰苦的斗争
for the good of the people
without caring much for any of ‘em.
为了人民的利益
没有去在意太多关于他们的。
And I look a lot worse without my wig.
并且当我没有这个法官帽的时候，我看见了太多糟糕的事情
The people elected me! To represent them!
人民选择了我！我代表他们！
To lead them! And I lead!
You ought to try it!
去领导他们！
你应该去尝试做它！
I admire your zeal, Mr. Stevens,
我赞扬你的热情，Mr. Stevens,
and I have tried to profit
from the example of it.
并且我试图从它的一些样本中得。
If I’d listened to you,
I’d’ve declared every slave free
如果我听从你的讲话，
我将宣布所有奴隶自由
the minute the first shell
struck Fort Sumter.
这个第一份炮弹将会在萨穆特堡。
Then the border states would’ve
gone over to the confederacy,
然后这些边境邦将不会倒向南部政府，
the war would’ve been lost
and the Union along with it,
这个战争将会结束，
联盟将和它一道向前，
and instead of abolishing slavery,
as we hope to do in two weeks,
而不是废除奴隶制度，
我们希望在两个星期之内完成它，
we’d be watching helpless
as infants as it spread
由于它的传播，我们将看起来像婴儿那样软弱无助
from the American South
into South America.
从美国南部到南美洲。
STEVENS: Oh God, how you
have longed to say that to me.
STEVENS:噢，天哪，你怎么这么想对我说这些。
You claim you trust them.
But you know what the people are.
你声称你信任他们。
但是你知道他们是什么人吗。
You know that the inner compass
that should direct the soul toward justice
你知道，内心的指南针将引导我们的灵魂走向正义
has ossified in white men
and women, north and south,
在南部和北部，那些白人男人和女人的思维已经僵化，
unto utter uselessness
through tolerating the evil of slavery.
绝对无法承认通过该死的奴隶制度。
White people cannot bear
the thought of sharing
白人无法忍受这种和黑人均分的观点
this country’s infinite
abundance with Negroes.
这个国家里面充斥着大量的黑人。
A compass, I learnt when
I was surveying, it’ll...
这个指南针，当我学会了测量，它将....
it’ll point you True North
from where you’re standing,
它将在你站的地方为你指向真正的北方，
but it’s got no advice about the swamps
但是它没法给你通知中途的沼泽
and deserts and chasms that
you’ll encounter along the way.
沙漠和悬崖，
以及一些你可能在路上忽然遇到的困境。
If in pursuit of your destination,
you plunge ahead, heedless of obstacles,
如果在追求你目的地的过程中，
你只顾向前，对阻碍不加注意，
and achieve nothing more
than to sink in a swamp...
你不会比你直接沉没在沼泽里面得到更多...
What’s the use of knowing True North?
你知道真正的北方有什么用处吗？
LINCOLN: Robert’s gonna
plead with us to let him enlist.
林肯：Robert将要向我们恳求，允许他加入军队。
Make time to talk to Robbie.
找个时间和Robbie谈谈。
You only have time for Tad.
– But Tad’s young.
你只有时间花在Tad身上。
-但是Tad还很年轻。
MARY: So is Robert.
Too young for the army.
MARY: 那么Robert呢.
他加入军队也太年轻了。
Plenty of boys younger
than Robert signing up...
很多比Robert还要年轻的小伙子都加入了...
Don’t take Robbie.
别想带走Robbie.
Don’t let me lose my son.
不要让我失去我的儿子。
[Knocking on door]
Go away! We’re occupied!
走开！我们正忙！
NICOLAY: Secretary Stanton has sent over
to tell you that as of half an hour ago,
NICOLAY: Stanton秘书已经在半个小时前派人过来叫你了，
the shelling of Wilmington
harbor has commenced.
Wilmington港的炮击已经开始了。
STANTON: They cannot possibly
maintain under this kind of an assault.
STANTON: 在这么猛烈的攻击下，他们不可能坚持下去。
Terry’s got ten thousand men
surrounding the Goddamned fort,
Terry得到了10000名士兵包围了Goddamned堡，
why doesn’t he answer my cables?
– WELLES: Fort Fisher
他为什么不回答我的电报？
– WELLES:费雪堡
is a mountain of a building, Edwin.
是成堆的建筑，Edwin.
MAJOR ECKERT: It’s the
largest fort they have, sir.
MAJOR ECKERT:这是他们拥有的最大的城堡，先生。
WELLES: Twenty-two big
seacoast guns on each rampart.
WELLES: 22门巨大的海岸炮在城墙上面。
MAJOR ECKERT: They’ve been
reinforcing it for the last two years
MAJOR ECKERT:在这最后2年里面，他们还不停地补强它。
STANTON: They’ve taken 17,000
shells since yesterday!
STANTON: 他们从昨天起就用了17,000炮弹！
I want to hear that Fort Fisher is ours
and Wilmington has fallen!
我希望听见费血堡是我们的了，并且Wilmington已经沦陷的消息！
Send another damn cable!
给其他混蛋发送电报！
The problem’s their
commander. Whiting!
问题是他们的指挥官。Whiting!
He engineered the fortress himself.
The damned thing’s his child.
他亲自设计这个城堡。
这个该死的地方就像他的孩子。
He’ll defend it till his every last man
is gone. He is not thinking...
他将保卫它，知道他的每一个士兵都阵亡。
他没有理智...
LINCOLN (SHOUTING):
“Come on out, you old rat!”
林肯（大叫）：
“出来，你这个老叛徒！”
LINCOLN: That’s what...
林肯：那是什么....
That' what Ethan Allen called to the
commander of Fort Ticonderogain in 1776.
那个就是在1776年被Ethan Allen称为Ticonderogain堡的指挥官。
“Come on out, you old rat!”
“出来，你这个老叛徒！”
Aah, ‘course there were only forty
odd redcoats at Ticonderoga.
啊哈，‘这是只有一个四十多岁的红衣军人在Ticonderoga.
But there is one
Ethan Allen story that I’m...
但是这个有一个Ethan Allen的故事，我...
– STANTON: No!
– .. very partial to...
– STANTON: 不！
– ..非常偏爱...
No, you’re... you’re
going to tell a story!
不，你是...你是
要讲故事吗！
I don’t believe... that I can bear...
我不相信...我能容忍...
to listen to another one
of your stories right now!
现在去听你的另一个故事！
STANTON: I need the B&O sideyard
schedules for Alexandria!
STANTON:我需要 Alexandria的B&O sideyard时间表！
I asked for them this morning!
我在今天早上问过他们！
[Lincoln laughing]
It was right after the Revolution,
right after peace had been concluded,
这是对的在革命之后，
在和平结束时候是对的，
and, hum...
那么，嗯...
Ethan Allen went to London to help our
Ethan Allen来伦敦去帮助我们
new country conduct
its business with the king.
和国王一起引导新国家的经济。
The English sneered at how rough we are,
这个英国人会嘲笑我们如何粗鲁，
and rude and simple-minded
and on like that,
没礼貌和头脑简单，就像那样，
everywhere he went, till one day
he was invited to the townhouse
他去过每一个地方，直到一天他被邀请进入市政府
of a great English lord.
一个伟大的英国贵族的。
Dinner was served, beverages imbibed,
度过了晚宴，喝点饮料，
time passed, as happens, and
随着时间流逝
Mr. Allen found he needed the privy.
Allen先生发现他需要它。
He was grateful to be directed thence.
他从那个时候起被控制起来。
Relieved, you might say.
也许，你可能会讲。
[Everyone laughs]
Now, Mr. Allen discovered
现在，Allen发现
on entering the water closet that
the only decoration therein was a...
在进入洗手间的时候，他发现其中唯一的装饰是一个...
a portrait of George Washington.
乔治 华盛顿的肖像画。
Ethan Allen done what he came to do,
Ethan Allen做完他要做的事情，
and returned to the drawing room.
然后回到了休息室。
His host and the others were disappointed
东道主和其他人都非常的失望
when he didn’t mention
Washington’s portrait.
当他没有说起华盛顿的肖像画的时候。
And finally His Lordship couldn’t resist,
最终贵族大人没有忍住，
and asked Mr. Allen had he noticed it,
问了Allen先生的评价，
the picture of Washington. He had.
他拥有的华盛顿的肖像画。
What did he think of its placement, did it
seem appropriately located to Mr. Allen?
他对它的位置有什么意见，有没有可以安排给Allen先生安排的工作？
Mr. Allen said it did.
Mr. Allen 说这些.
His host was astounded!
Appropriate?
东道主非常的吃惊！
合适的？
George Washington’s likeness
in a water closet?
乔治 华盛顿的肖像画在洗手间里面？
Yes, said Mr. Allen, where
it’ll do good service.
是的，Allen先生说，在那里它给做良好的服务。
The whole world knows
nothing’ll make an Englishman shit
整个世界都知道，没有东西可以使一个英国男人讨厌
quicker than the sight
of George Washington.
超过乔治 华盛顿。
[Everyone laughs]
I love that story.
我喜欢这个故事。
[Cable telegraph clicking]
CHARLES BENJAMIN: Fort Fisher
is ours. We’ve taken the port.
CHARLES BENJAMIN: 费血堡是我们的了，我们拿下了它。
WELLES: And Wilmington?
WELLES:Wilmington怎么样？
ECKERT: We’ve taken the fort, but the
city of Wilmington has not surrendered.
ECKERT:我们已经那些了那个城堡，但是Wilmington还没有投降。
STANTON: How many casualties?
STANTON: 人员伤亡怎么样？
– FERNANDO WOOD: Heavy losses.
– GEORGE PENDLETON: And more to come.
– FERNANDO WOOD: 损失惨重。
– GEORGE PENDLETON:未来还有更多。
WOOD: Sours the national mood.
WOOD: 糟糕的国民情绪。
That might suffice to discourage him...
– PENDLETON: To bring this down?
这个可能能够足够阻止他....
– PENDLETON: 把这些停止吗？
Not in a fight like this.
This is to the death.
没有一个战争像这样。
这是在制造死亡。
WOOD: It’s gruesome!
WOOD: 这是非常可怕的！
PENDLETON: Are you despairing,
or merely lazy?
PENDLETON: 你感觉到了绝望了吗，或者
仅仅只是这样的？
This fight is for The United States
of America. Nothing “suffices”!
这是为了整个美国的战斗，不是仅仅在满足谁的需要！
A rumor? Nothing!
谣言吗？没事！
They’re not lazy.
They’re busily buying votes!
他们并不懒惰。
他们正忙着在购买选票！
While we hope to be saved
by “the national mood?!”
虽然我们希望可以拯救‘国民情绪’
Before this blood is dry,
when Stevens next takes the floor,
在血液凝固之前，
当 Stevens下一个发言的时候，
taunt him. You excel at that.
嘲笑他。你擅长做这些。
Get him to proclaim what we all know
he believes in his coal-colored heart:
让他去宣传那些我们都知道的
他用他那颗黑色的心里面相信的：
that this vote is meant to set the
black race on high, to niggerate America.
这个投票时为了提高黑色人种的地位，为了美国黑人。
WOOD: George, please. Stay on course.
WOOD:乔治，请。待在这里。
PENDLETON: Bring Stevens to full froth.
PENDLETON: 许给Stevens那些无意义的空谈
I can ensure that every newspaperman
from Louisville to San Francisco
我能确定所有从Louisville到San Francisco的报社记者
will be here to witness it and print it.
将在这里见证和出版它。
SCHUYLER COLFAX: The floor
belongs to the mellifluent gentleman
SCHUYLER COLFAX:发言权是属于上等的绅士的
from Kentucky,
Mr. George Yeaman.
来自Kentucky，
YEAMAN: I thank you, Speaker Colfax.
YEAMAN: 我很感激你，Colfax议长。
Although... I’m disgusted by slavery
尽管...我非常的厌恶奴隶制
I rise on this sad and solemn day.
我在这个悲伤，严肃的日子里。
to announce that I’m
opposed to the amendment.
宣布我反对修正法案。
We must consider what
will become of colored folk
我们必须考虑我们将变成一个多色彩的种族
if four million are in
one instant set free.
如果四百万的黑人立即被释放。
LITTON: They’ll be free, George.
That’s what’ll become of them!
LITTON: 他们将自由，乔治。
这将会变成什么样！
SCHELL: Think how splendid
if Mr. Yeaman switched.
SCHELL: 想想多么的辉煌吧，如果 Yeaman先生转变了。
LATHAM: Too publicly against us.
He can’t change course now.
LATHAM: 太多的人反抗我们。
他不能改变现状。
BILBO: Not for some
miserable little job anyways.
BILBO: 不管怎么样，不是为了一些小小的可怜的家伙工作的。
我们将被迫释放
男人的有色种族
We will be forced to enfranchise
the men of the colored race.
这将不再是不人道的
It would be inhuman not to!
在我们周围的人准备给黑人投票
Who among us is prepared
to give Negroes the vote?
[boos throughout the chamber]
YEAMAN: And, and!
嘘声响亮整个教室
对于那应该遵循什么
What shall follow upon that?
全体解放
Universal enfranchisement?
抽票给你女人？
Votes for women?
[Cheers and boos]
干杯欢呼
保佑我的眼睛，如果它不是
俄亥俄州的邮政局长
WOOD: Bless my eyes, if it isn’t the
Post Master of Millersburg Ohio!
LeClerk先生觉得应该要通知我们
PENDLETON: Mr. LeClerk felt
honor-bound to inform us
你们恶心的背叛
of your disgusting betrayal.
出卖你们的灵魂
Your prostitution.
那是真的吗？Hawkins邮政局长
WOOD: Is that true, Postmaster Hawkins?
是你的文雅的美德吗？
Is your maidenly virtue for sale?
如果我的邻居听到
我给“黑人自由”投了赞成票
HAWKINS: If my neighbors hear
that I voted yes for nigger freedom
没有得到和平，他们会杀了我
and no to peace, they will kill me.
一言为定，你们男人
知道比你尿裤子好
BILBO: A deal is a deal and you men
know better than to piss your pants
就关于和平的话题
just cause there’s talk
about peace talks.
等着瞧，我会找到其他工作
– HAWKINS: Look, I’ll find another job.
我的邻居都在纳什维尔
– BILBO:My neighbors in Nashville,
他们发现我忠于联盟，差点把我阉了
they found out I was loyal to the Union,
they came after me with gelding knives!
任何其他工作
– HAWKINS: Any other job!
你做的对，Clay Hawkins..
– BILBO: You do right, Clay Hawkins...
– HAWKINS: I want to do right!
– BILBO: and make yourself some money...
– HAWKINS:我想做对的事
– BILBO:自己也要挣些钱
..在讨价还价!
BILBO: .. in the bargain!
但是我没有勇气
– HAWKINS: But I got no courage!
等下，你想，纳税人对西方储备是什么
BILBO: Wait!! You wanted, what was it,
tax man for the Western Reserve,
你可以拥有整个俄亥俄州如果你,,,废话
hell you can have the whole
state of Ohio if you... Aw, crap.
11个投票？
SEWARD: Eleven votes?!
2天前我们有12张
怎么回事？
Two days ago we had twelve!
What happened?
在Richmond有叛变
– There are defections in the Richmond...
这个该死的谣言....
– It’s the goddamned rumors regarding...
是的，和平组织提供
– LATHAM: Yes! The peace offer!
毫无根据
– SEWARD: Groundless
我告诉你了
SEWARD: I told you that.
然而谣言四起。
– LATHAM: And yet the rumors persist.
他们正在破坏我们
SCHELL: They are ruining us.
在那些可信的为数不多的代表中
Among the few remaining representatives
who seem remotely plausible
有一个可察觉的
增加的阻力
there is a perceptible
increase in resistance.
阻力，去死！
BILBO: Resistance, hell!
Thingamabob Hollister，来自印第安纳州的民主党?
Thingamabob Hollister, Dem from Indiana?
我走进他，the sumbitch
靠近我要谋杀我
I approached him, the sumbitch
near to murdered me!
可能你推动的太强硬了
– SEWARD: Perhaps you push too hard.
我没有推动任何人
– BILBO: I push nobody.
可能我们需要增援部队
Perhaps we need reinforcements.
如果Jeff Davis想停止敌对行动,
If Jeff Davis wants to cease hostilities,
你认为谁会给一个诚恳的固体大便去解放奴隶
who do you think’ll give a genuine
solid shit to free slaves?
回到那去
Get back to it.
男士们，大家好
SEWARD: And gentlemen, good day.
我们正处于僵局。
SCHELL: We are at an impasse.
告诉林肯
否认这个谣言，公开。
LATHAM: Tell Lincoln to
deny the rumors. Publicly.
告诉我们您对我们的期望是什么
SCHELL: Tell us what you expect of us.
我期望你去做你的工作
SEWARD: I expect you to do your work.
并有足够的感觉和味觉
不想通知总统
And to have sufficient sense and taste
not to presume to instruct the President.
或者我
Or me.
有没有一个同盟国提供？
SCHELL: Is there a
Confederate offer or not?
先生们
GRANT: Gentlemen...
我建议你改变一下你的提议
I suggest you work some
changes to your proposal
在你把它给总统之前
before you give it to the President.
我们渴望成为在我们去华盛顿的路上
We’re eager to be on
our way to Washington.
林肯先生让你告诉我们
ALEXANDER STEPHENS: Did
Mr. Lincoln tell you to tell us this?
这意思是。。。“确保
GRANT: It says...“securing peace...
我们2个国家的和平”像之前那样继续下去
for our two countries.”
And it goes on like that.
我不知道你。。。只有一个国家
– I don’t know what you...
– There’s just one country.
你和我，我们是那个国家的文化
And you and I, we’re
citizens of that country.
我要保护它通过武装叛乱。
I’m fighting to protect it
from armed rebels.
通过你
From you.
Blair先生,他告诉我们，他...
Mr-Mr. Blair, he-he told us, he...
他告诉总统Davis我们是。。。
he told President Davis we were...
一个公民像Preston Blair可以说什么
A private citizen like Preston Blair
can say what he pleases
since he has no authority over anything.
当他没有权力，任何东西。
如果你想跟总统林肯讨论和平问题
If you want to discuss peace
with President Lincoln,
要考虑
consider revisions.
如果我们不讨论休战
交战国之间
If we’re not to discuss a truce
between warring nations,
关于天堂命名我们可以讨论什么？
what in heaven’s name can we discuss?
投降的条件
Terms of surrender.
“办公室美国军事电报战争部亚伯拉罕林肯
GRANT: “Office United States Military
Telegraph War Dept. For Abraham Lincoln,
美国总统
1月20,1865
President of the United States,
January 20, 1865.
我将机密地陈述
我相信，
I will state confidentially
that I am convinced,
跟这些委员谈话
upon conversation with
these Commissioners,
他们的意图是好的
和他们的愿望，真诚
that their intentions are good
and their desire sincere
恢复和平与联盟。
to restore peace and union.
我担心他们回去，
没有任何的利益表达。”
I fear now their going back,
without any expression of interest.”
[Seward’s voice takes over]
“……从任何当局，
林肯先生会有不好的影响。”
“...from anyone in authority,
Mr. Lincoln will have a bad influence.”
我很抱歉保证你不可能
“I will be sorry should it
prove impossible for you
跟他们有一个面试
to have an interview with them.
我在等你的指示。
I am awaiting your instructions.
美国批准，中尉美国“指挥军队
U.S. Grant, Lieutenant General
Commanding Armies United States”.
再战争开始4年后大约600000人死亡
After four years of war and...
near 600,000 lives lost,
他现在相信我们可以结束战争了
he believes we can end this war now.
我相信他信到骨子里去了。
My trust in him is marrow deep.
你可以带代表去华盛顿
SEWARD: You could bring
the delegates to Washington.
交换南方立即投降，
In exchange for the South’s
immediate surrender,
我们可以给他们该修正案的失败。
we could promise them
the amendment’s defeat.
他们同意了，你认为呢？
They’d agree, don’t you think?
我们结束战争了，这个星期
We’d end the war. This week.
或者如果你可以管理，貌似不用做这个，
Or if you could manage,
without seeming to do it, to....
和平代表团可能会遇到
拖延当他们旅行到杰姆斯河
The peace delegation might encounter
delays as they travel up the James River.
特别是威尔明顿周围的战斗。
Particularly with the
fighting around Wilmington.
在十天的时间，我们可以通过第十三条修正案。
Within ten days time, we might
pass the Thirteenth Amendment.
这是个16岁大的男孩
LINCOLN: Here’s a sixteen year old boy.
他们会提起他
They’re gonna hang him...
他与印第安娜一起第十五加略山附近的博福特，
He was with the 15th Indiana
Calvary near Beaufort,
似乎他跛马避战
seems he lamed his horse to avoid battle.
我不认为斯坦顿会抱怨，如果我打断他，
I don’t think even Stanton
would complain if I pardoned him,
你认为斯坦顿会抱怨？
You think Stanton would complain?
我不知道，先生我不知道你是谁
JOHN HAY: I don’t know, sir,
I don’t know who you’re, uh...
几点了
What time is it?
现在早上3点40
LINCOLN: It’s three forty in the morning.
不要让他再打算了秘书
NICOLAY: Don’t let him pardon any more deserters...
哦，Mr. Stanton
HAY: Aah, Mr. Stanton
认为你打断太多次了
thinks you pardon too many.
他是一般中风，对这
He’s generally apoplectic on the subject.
他不应该这样做，
LINCOLN: He oughtn’t to have done that,
削弱了他的马，那是残酷的，
crippled his horse, that was cruel,
but you don’t just hang
a sixteen year old boy for that...
但是你只是不能提起一个16岁男孩
问horse他在想什么
HAY: Ask the horse what he thinks.
残酷的。没有一个十六岁的男孩留下。
.. for cruelty. There’d be no
sixteen year old boys left.
Grant想要我带secesh代表去华盛顿
Grant wants me to bring
the secesh delegates to Washington.
因此有secesh的代表吗？
HAY: So there are secesh delegates?
他害怕，那就是全部
LINCOLN: He was afraid, that’s all it was.
我也不在乎因为害怕而绞死一个男孩
I don’t care to hang a boy
for being frightened, either.。
他有什么好处呢？
What good would it do him?
战争差不多结束了，不是这样吗？
War’s nearly done, ain’t that so?
再用一个尸体干什么？
What use one more corpse?
还有尸体吗？
Any more corpses?
你需要伙伴吗？
HAY: Do you need company?
在这样的时刻，我最好一个人。
LINCOLN: In times like this,
I’m best alone.
“中将Ulysses S. Grant,城市点。
LINCOLN: “Lieutenant General
Ulysses S. Grant, City Point.
我已经带着兴趣听你的话。”
I have read your words with interest.”
我问，在访问Richmond委员这方面，
“I ask that, regardless
of any action I take
我问，在访问Richmond委员这方面，不管我采取任何行动，
in the matter of the visit
of the Richmond commissioners,
你保持在你的部队军事里准备战斗，
you maintain among your troops
military preparedness for battle,
as you have done until now.”
正如直到现在你所做的。”
“Have Captain Saunders convey the
commissioners to me here in Washington.”
“队长Saunders在华盛顿传达委员给我吗。”
“A. Lincoln” and the date.
– SAMUEL BECKWITH: Yes sir.
“A.Lincoln" 和日期。
– SAMUEL BECKWITH：是，先生。
Shall I transmit, sir?
要我传输吗，先生？
LINCOLN: You think we choose to be born?
LINCOLN:你认为我们能选择出生？
BECKWITH: I don’t suppose so.
BECKWITH:我不这样认为。
LINCOLN: Are we fitted to
the times we’re born into?
LINCOLN:我们适合于我们出生的时代？
BECKWITH: Well, I don’t know about myself.
BECKWITH: 好，我不知道我自己。
You may be...
sir. Fitted.
你也许。。。
先生，适合。
What do you reckon?
你在想什么？
HOMER BATES: Well, I’m an engineer.
HOMER BATES:好，我是一个工程师。
BATES: I reckon there’s machinery but...
no one’s done the fitting.
BATES:我想这是机械装置，但是。。。
没人完成配件。
LINCOLN: You’re an engineer. You must
know Euclid’s axioms and common notions.
LINCOLN:你是个工程师。你一定知道欧几里德原理和常见概念。
BATES: I must’ve in school, but...
我必须已经在学校里，但是。。。
LINCOLN: I never had much
of schooling, but I read Euclid,
我从没学习，但是我读过欧几里德，
in an old book I borrowed.
在我借过的旧书里。
Little enough ever found
its way in here, but...
在这里没有足够的发现，但是。。。
once learnt it stayed learnt.
曾经学过一直在学。
Euclid’s first common notion is this:
欧几里德的第一个常见概念是这个：
“Things which are equal to the
same thing are equal to each other.”
“同样的事情彼此平等。”
That’s a rule of mathematical reasoning.
这是一个数学推理的规则。
It’s true because it works.
这是正确的因为它起作用。
Has done and always will do.
已经完成了并且总是会做的。
In his book, hmm...
在他的书里，恩。。。
Euclid says this is
“self-evident.”
欧几里德说这是“不言自明。”
D’you see, there it is, even in that two
thousand year old book of mechanical law:
你没看见，在那儿，甚至在两千年的机械法的老书：
it is a self evident truth that things
which are equal to the same thing
这是一个不言而喻的真理，同样的事情都是平等的
are equal to each other.
都是平等的
We begin with equality.
我开始于平等。
That’s the origin, isn’t it?
那是原点，不是吗？
That balance, that's... that’s fairness.
那种平衡，那是。。。那是公平的。
That’s justice.
那是正义。
Just read me back the last
sentence of that telegram, please.
请读回我电报的最后一句话。
BECKWITH: “Have Captain Saunders convey
the commissioners to me here in Washington.”
队长Sauders在华盛顿有传达委员给我吗。
A slight emendation if you would, Sam.
如果你能稍微校正，山姆。
“Have Captain Saunders convey
the gentlemen aboard the River Queen
队长Saunders有传达先生们在Queen河
as far as Hampton Roads, Virginia,
直到Hampton Roads,Virginia,
and there wait until...”
那里等到。。。
“.. further advice from me.”
我更一步建议。
“Do not proceed to Washington.”
不要继续去华盛顿。
COLFAX: The World, the Herald
and the Times, New York, Chicago,
世界，《先驱报》和《纽约时报》，纽约，芝加哥
the Journal of Commerce,
even your hometown paper’s here.
《商业日报》，即使你这家乡的报纸。
ASHLEY: Say you believe only
in legal equality for all races,
说你相信所有种族法律平等，
not racial quality. I beg you, sir.
不是种族质量。我祈求你，先生。
Compromise.
妥协。
Or you risk it all.
或者你冒险。
WOOD: I’ve asked you a question,
Mr. Stevens, and you must answer me.
我问你一个问题，Mr.Stevens,你必须回答我。
Do you or do you not hold
that the precept that
你支持或者不支持这个规则
“all men are created equal”
is meant literally?
“所有男人生来平等”。是字面的意思吗？
这不是修正案的真正目的？
WOOD (CONT’D): Is that not the
true purpose of the amendment?
促进你的终极和热心的梦想提升。。。
To promote your ultimate and
ardent dream to elevate...
修正案真实的目的，wood先生，
STEVENS: The true purpose
of the amendment, Mr. Wood,
你完全命名，无头脑的，阻碍对象？
you perfectly-named,
brainless, obstructive object?
[Everyone laughing]
现在你一直坚持，Stevens先生，
Now you have always insisted, Mr. Stevens,
黑人和白人是一样的。
that Negroes are the same
as white men are.
修正案的真实目的。。。
The true purpose of the amendment...
[Chamber totally silent]
我不赞成一切事物平等，
I don’t hold with equality in all things,
只有人人平等
没有更多的法律。
only with equality before
the law and nothing more.
这不是如此!
你…
That’s not so!
You...
你要相信黑人跟白人完全平等
You believe that Negroes
are entirely equal to white men.
你已经说过上百次了
不要脸!不要脸!
You’ve said it a thousand times...
For shame! For shame!
停止支吾其词和问答
代表好运
Stop prevaricating and answer,
Representative Wood!
对于所有事，我不能把握平等对待
I don’t hold with equality in all things,
只要平等
only with equality...
在几白年后
– After the decades
不再有其他
STEVENS: .. and nothing more!
他回答了你的问题
He's answered your questions!
这个修正案已化为乌有
关于种族平等!
This amendment has naught
to do with race equality!
– S: I don’t hold with equality in all things...
– P: You have long insisted, have you not...
– S:我不把握所有事都是平等的
– P:你要长时间坚持,你没有…
在法律前只有平等
– S: only with equality before the law...
黄昏的有色种族.
– P: that the dusk colored race...
不再有其他
– S: and nothing more.
跟白人没有区别
– P: is no different from the white one.
MARY:谁曾经猜到那个以前
这样的控制能力的噩梦?
MARY: Who’d ever’ve guessed that old
nightmare capable of such control?
他总有一天可能会成为一个政治家
He might make a politician someday...
我要走了
– MRS. KECKLEY: I need to go.
Keykley夫人!
– MARY: Mrs. Keykley!
你的疯狂试图
欺骗我们现在是不值得的一个代表
PENDLETON: Your frantic attempt to delude us
now is unworthy of a representative.
这不是事实，对白人不值得
It is in fact, unworthy of a white man!
我怎样去控制所有的人都平等的
How can I hold that all men
are created equal,
在这里我面前站,散发出恶臭,
when here before me stands, stinking,
道德的尸体
来自俄亥俄州的绅士,
the moral carcass of
the gentleman from Ohio,
证明有些男人低人一等,
proof that some men are inferior,
赋予他们的制造商和暗淡的智慧
endowed by their Maker with dim wits,
透明的原因
与寒冷苍白的粘液
impermeable to reason
with cold pallid slime
在他们的血管里代替热血
in their veins instead
of hot red blood!
你比其他人更像爬行动物，George,
You are more reptile than man, George,
如此低和扁平人类的足迹
不能粉碎你!
so low and flat that the foot of man
is incapable of crushing you!
PENDLETON:你怎么敢这样！
How dare you!
你也是，Pendleton,
Yet even you, Pendleton,
谁应该被gibbetted吗
以叛国罪长在,今天之前
who should have been gibbetted
for treason long before today,
即使是毫无价值的不值得你应该
要在法律面前平等!
even worthless unworthy you ought
to be treated equally before the law!
[Everyone cheers and applauds]
再一次，先生，再一次，我说：
And so again, sir, and again
and again and again I say:
我不能把握对每件事都平等
I DO NOT HOLD WITH
EQUALITY IN ALL THINGS.
只有在法律前平等
ONLY WITH EQUALITY BEFORE THE LAW.
Speaker先生,
PENDLETON: Mr. Speaker,
你会允许这个卑鄙的粗鲁的男人
will you permit this vile boorish man
诽谤ant来威胁我吗,…
to slander ant to threaten me and...
你说。。如果我很惊喜
LITTON: You asked... if ever I was surprised.
今天，Stevens先生,
Today... Mr. Stevens,
我很惊喜
I was surprised.
你已经领导了民族平等的运动30年了
You’ve led the battle for
race equality for thirty years!
对国家的未来来说，这是每个希望的基础
The basis of... of every hope
for this country’s future life,
你否认黑人平等
you denied Negro equality!
对此，我很恶心
I’m nauseated.
你否定去说所有人类，好吧...人类
You refused to say that all
humans are, well... human!
Stevens先生，你遗失了你的灵魂吗？
Have you lost your very soul, Mr. Stevens
那没有你要说的吗？
Is there nothing you won’t say?
我很抱歉你很令人恶心，Asa
I’m sorry you’re nauseous, Asa,
那肯定会很不客气的
that must be unpleasant.
我想修正法案同过
I want the amendment to pass.
结果第一宪法跟提及的奴隶制
So that the Constitution’s first
and only mention of slavery
是被绝对禁止的
is its absolute prohibition.
对于这个修正案，对于我生命中所工作的一切
For this amendment, for which
I have worked all of my life
对于不计其数的有色人种
and for which countless colored men
我们要战斗直到死亡
and women have fought and died
上百，上千的士兵
and now hundreds of
thousands of soldiers.
不，先生
No, sir, no.
这看起来像我没有说任何事
It seems there is very
nearly nothing I won’t say.
我不会下钻
RERT: I’m not going in.
你说你想帮我
LINCOLN: You said you wanted to help me.
这是....这在抵抗方面很笨重的
This is... This is just a clumsy
attempt at discouragement.
我已经到了军医院
I’ve been to army hospitals,
我看到了诊所
I’ve seen surgeries,
我跟妈妈去看看疟疾驳船
I went and visited the
malaria barges with mama.
她告诉我她没有带你进去
LINCOLN: She told me
she didn’t take you inside.
后来我潜进去了。我看到那没有任何变化
I snuck in afterwards. I’ve seen
what it’s like, this changes nothing.
在所有的评估下，我很高兴我拥有你的公司
At all rates, I’m happy
to have your company.
早上好，Jim
LINCOLN: Morning, Jim.
您好，总统先生
ARMY SURGEON: Hello, Mr. President.
很高兴又看到你了
LINCOLN: Good to see you again.
好孩子，第一个问题：你吃饱了吗？
Well boys, first question:
You getting enough to eat?
您好，总统先生
FIRST PATIENT: Hello, sir.
你叫什么名字，士兵？
– What’s your name, soldier?
Robert
– Robert.
Robert。很高兴认识你，Robert
Robert. Good to meet you, Robert.
很高兴认识你
KEVIN: Nice to meet you.
你叫什么？
– What’s your name?
Kevin
– Kevin.
告诉我你以前叫什么。
Tell me your names as I go past.
我想知道我在跟谁说话。Kevin
I like to know who I’m talkin’ to. Kevin.
总统先生，我叫John
– Mr. President, John.
John
– John.
我以前见过你
I’ve seen you before.
总统先生...
– Mr. President...
你确定你分到牛排，我不介意...
LINCOLN: Make sure you get
some steak, I wouldn’t mind...
怎么回事，Bob?
LINCOLN: What’s the matter, Bob?
我一定要做到！
I have to do this!
我会做到的，我不需要你的允许才能入伍
And I will do it and I don’t
need your permission to enlist.
从战争开始以来，同样的演讲
That same speech has been
made by how many sons,
对多少孩子跟多少爸爸说过？
to how many fathers since the war began?
我不需要你那该死的允许
“I don’t need your damn permission,
你这可恶的老家伙
you miserable old goat,
不管如何我都会入伍的
I'm gonna enlist anyhow!”
无数的父亲没法说给他们的儿子听
And what wouldn’t those
numberless fathers have given
to be able to say to their sons as...
我立刻说给我的儿子听
I now say to mine,
我是总司令
”I’m commander-in-chief,
所以实际上，没有我的允许
so in point of fact,
without my permission,
你不会应募进任何地方，年轻人
you ain’t enlisting in nothing,
nowhere, young man.”
是你害怕的妈妈
It’s mama you’re scared of,
不是我杀得
not me getting killed.
我一定要做到！我会做到的！
I have to do this! And I will!
或者我会羞耻与我安于现状的生活
Or I will feel ashamed of myself
for the rest of my life.
你的斗争与否无关紧要
Whether or not you fought
is what’s gonna matter.
不只是对其他人来说，而是我来说
And not just to other people,
but to myself.
我不是你，pa。我不可以做那些事
I won’t be you, pa. I can’t do that.
但是我不想一事无成
But I don’t want to be nothing.
他会没事的Molly
LINCOLN: He’ll be fine, Molly.
全市人民的意愿是想远离前线，远离战争
City Point’s away back from
the front lines, from the fighting,
他会成为一个为了统筹财政补贴而传递消息的副官
he’ll be an adjutant running
messages for General Grant.
战争会杀了我们的儿子的
The war will take our son!
一名狙击手或者投弹手，又或者炮手！
A sniper, or a shrapnel
shell, or typhus!
跟以前带走Willie一样
Same as took Willie,
一天中 上百名孩子牺牲了！
it takes hundreds of boys a day!
他会无用的死去，我怎么才能原谅你？
He’ll die uselessly, and how
will I ever forgive you?
大部分男人，他们的第一个孩子是他们的最爱，但是你，
Most men, their firstborn
is their favorite, but you,
你永远是一个该死的Robert
you’ve always blamed Robert
for being born,
让你陷于婚姻中就是你的悲哀
for trapping you in a marriage
that’s only ever given you grief
让你后悔
and caused you regret.
那是非常不正确的
– LINCOLN: That’s simply not true.
如果跟Grant一样寒风港的屠杀是你一手造成的话，上帝帮帮我把
And if the slaughter of Cold Harbor is on
your hands same as Grant, God help us!
我们要背负很多杀人罪基于你下的命令
We’ll pay for the oceans of
spilled blood you’ve sanctioned,
我们要和我们的后代去偿还不计其数的尸体
the uncountable corpses we’ll be
made to pay with our son’s dear blood.
就，就只是这些， Lincoln总统
Just, just this once, Mrs. Lincoln,
我需要你那宽广而不自私的观点
I demand of you to try and take the
liberal and not the selfish point of view.
Robert不会原谅他自己的
Robert will never forgive himself.
你想像一下他原谅了我们
You imagine he''ll forgive us
如果我们继续去遏制他自然的心性
if we continue to stifle his
very natural ambition?!
如果我拒绝提供宽敞的道路
And if I refuse to take the highroad,
如果我不取消粗燥不平的老路
if I won’t take up the rough old cross,
你会再次在精神病院吓我，
will you threaten me again
with the madhouse,
当我没有为了Willie停止哭泣时
as you did when I couldn’t
stop crying over Willie,
当我向你表现心碎真正的心碎那样
when I showed you what heartbreak,
real heartbreak looked like,
你不会有勇气去赞同的，去帮我
and you hadn’t the courage
to countenance it, to help me...
对。那时你安慰那个小孩子而去回绝很多事的时候...
LINCOLN: That’s right. When you
refused so much as to comfort Tad...
我和Willie在房间里
– M: I was in the room with Willie,
那个没病的孩子
– L: the child who was not only sick,
我拦不住他...
– M: I was holding him...
但是他发狂了
– L: but beside himself with grief?
当他死了的时候我武装起来了
– M: in my arms as he died!
但是你的悲伤，你的悲伤，你的....
– L: Oh but your grief, your grief, your...
无尽的悲伤
L: inexhaustible grief!
你是多么勇敢的把它投给了我？！
– M: How dare you throw that at me?!
这个母亲不会让他接近她的
– L: And his mother won’t let him near her,
我不能让那个小孩子进来
– M: I couldn’t let Tad in!
因为她从早上到晚上一直在尖叫
– L: ‘cos she’s screaming from morning to night,
我不能让她威胁到他
– M: I couldn’t risk him
看我多么愤怒
M: seeing how angry I was!
在走廊起搏
– L: pacing the corridors,
在阴影中家具上嚎叫，就像幽灵
howling at shadows
and furniture and ghosts!
我应当去做那件事，我应当为了小孩子而去奋斗
I ought to have done it, I ought
have done for Tad’s sake,
为了每个人的那些该死的原有
for everybody’s goddamned sake,
我应该把你关进精神病院
I should have clapped you in the madhouse!
那么去做啊！
Then do it!!
去做！你别吓到我
Do it! Don’t you threaten me,
你做的时候，把握锁起来
you do it this time, lock me away!
你一定要这么做，我发誓！
You’ll have to, I swear!
如果Robert被杀了...
If Robert is killed...
[Mary sobbing]
我不能让你为了Willie而伤心
I couldn’t tolerate you
grieving so for Willie
因为我自己不允许这件事发生
because I couldn’t permit it in myself,
知道我想的时候，Mary
though I wanted to, Mary.
我想跟他的棺材在地下墓穴里爬行
I wanted to crawl under the earth,
into the vault with his coffin.
我还是回去做的。每天都会
And I still do. Everyday I do.
别跟我倾诉悲伤
Don’t speak to me about grief.
我必须做出我的决定，
I must make my decisions,
Bob必须做出他的决定，你做你的决定
Bob must make his, you yours.
还有...承担我们必须承担的
And... bear what we must,
把握跟支持我们必须的
hold and carry what we must.
我不承担超出我的范围的事
What I carry within me,
你一定要答应
you must allow me to do it,
必须自己一个
alone as I must.
你很孤单，Mary
And you alone, Mary,
你很孤单
you alone...
应该减轻负担
may lighten this burden,
或者释放你的压力
or render it intolerable.
你自己选择
As you choose.
[Opera: Gounod’s Faust]
你认为我很无知吧
MARY: You think I’m ignorant
of what you’re up to
因为你没有跟我讨论你的计划
because you haven’t discussed this scheme
你应当做的计划
with me as you ought to have done.
什么时候我这么容易别你迷惑了？
When have I ever been
so easily bamboozled?
我相信你当你坚持修正宪法
I believe you when you insist
that amending the constitution
废除奴隶制的时候会结束这场战争
and abolishing slavery will end this war.
直到你叫我的儿子加入战场
And since you are sending
my son into the war,
如果你在修正法案战斗中失败你会很痛苦的
woe unto you if you fail
to pass the amendment.
Seward不想我留下肮脏的脚印在城镇里
Seward doesn’t want me leaving
big muddy footprints all over town.
没人会比你知道更多的
No one has ever lived who
knows better than you
关于在行骗的道路上的合适安置
the proper placement of
footfalls on treacherous paths.
Seward不可以做这件事
Seward can’t do it.
You must.
因为如果你未能得到所需的选票
Because if you fail to acquire
the necessary votes,
很混乱，总统先生，你要回答我
woe unto you, sir, you will answer to me.
我知道只有四天时间表决
MRS. KECKLEY: I know the
vote is only four days away.
我知道你担心
I know you’re concerned.
谢谢你的关心
Thank you for your concern over this,
我想 你知道他们会赞同的
and I want you to know,
they’ll approve it.
上帝会看到的
God will see to it.
我不会羡慕上帝的工作
LINCOLN: I don’t envy him His task.
他也许也在希望自己为了达成此次的目的
He may wish He’d chosen an
instrument for His purpose
能找到比众议院投票
more wieldy than the
更为行之有效的手段
House of Representatives.
那您会看到的
MRS. KECKLEY: Then you’ll see to it.
你为你们的未来感到担心吗
Are you afraid of what lies
ahead for your people?
如果我们胜利的话？
If we succeed?
白人不希望我们留在这里
White people don’t want us here.
很多人的确这么想的
– LINCOLN: Many don’t.
您呢？
– What about you?
我不知道你是怎么想的，凯克里太太
I don’t know you, Mrs. Keckley.
你们中的任何人我都不了解
Any of you.
你们是我所熟悉的人,就像周围的所有人一样
You’re familiar to me, as all people are.
我们都是无家可归，贫穷，
Unaccommodated, poor, bare,
食不果腹的造物
forked creatures such as we all are.
你有权期望我所期望的
You have a right to expect what I expect,
而我们能够理解彼此的期望
and likely our expectations are
not incomprehensible to each other.
我想我会习惯你们的
I assume I’ll get used to you.
但你们之于国家
But what you are to the nation,
之于奴隶制终结之时的未来，我仍不知道会是什么模样
what’ll become of you once slavery’s
day is done, I don’t know.
我无法断言我的人民会变成什么样子
What my people are to be, I can’t say.
我从没听到有人问起过自由带来的后果，自由是与生俱来的
I never heard any ask what
freedom will bring. Freedom’s a first.
对我而言
As for me...
我的儿子为联邦军作战，死在了战场上
My son died, fighting for the Union...
穿着联邦军的蓝色制服
wearing the Union blue.
他为自由而死
For freedom he died.
我是他的母亲
I’m his mother.
这便是我之于这个国家的意义，林肯先生
That’s what I am
to the nation, Mr. Lincoln.
我还能是什么别的呢？
What else must I be?
再过五秒我可就要凑齐一手了
BILBO: My whole hand’s gonna
be proud in about five seconds.
-  哦，是么？
– LATHAM: Oh, it is? What you got goin’?
让我看看你凑得多齐
– BILBO: Let’s see how proud you gonna be.
- 来啊？
– BILBO: Yeah?
- 别来烦！
– LATHAM: Go away!
那表带是金的么？
– LATHAM: That watch fob, is that gold?
- 别盯着那玩意看！
– BILBO: You keep your eyes off my fob!
- 先生们...
– SEWARD: Gentlemen...
- 对九
– LATHAM: Nines paired!
- 有客人来了
– SEWARD: .. you have a visitor.
- 哦该死！
– BILBO: Oh my God damn!
这下玩完了
Well, I’ll be fucked.
我也这么想，您是...？
I wouldn’t bet against it, Mr...?
- W.N.Bilbo
– W.N. Bilbo.
- 哦对，Bilbo先生
– Yeah, Mr. Bilbo.
- 先生们
Gentlemen.
先生...
– Sir...
您为什么会来这里？
BILBO: Why are you here?
我没有冒犯之意，但斯沃德先生
No offense, but Mr. Seward’s
不愿我们直呼您的名字
banished the very mention of your name,
他甚至不让我们用50美分的纸币，因为那上面印着您的头像
he won’t even let us use fifty-cent pieces
‘cause they got your face on ‘em.
国务卿把这事告诉我了
LINCOLN: The Secretary of
State here tells me that, uh,
你们从民主党那挣来了十一票，
you got eleven Democrats
真是振奋人心
in the bag, that’s encouraging.
哦，其实也没什么好高兴的，
LATHAM: Oh, you've got no
cause to be encouraged,
先生。呃...
Sir. Uh...
我们要被...解雇了么？
SCHELL: Are we being... fired?
“我们可都听见那午夜的钟声了，夏禄先生。”
LINCOLN: “We have heard the
chimes of midnight, Master Shallow.”
我来这里是来提醒你们年轻人，
伟大的最后审判日已经临近。
I’m here to alert you boys that the
great day of reckoning is nigh upon us.
SCHELL:
SCHELL: The Democrats
we’ve yet to bag, sir.
我们民主党还没有准备好，先生。
这个慈善工作不需要准备的。
The patronage jobs simply won’t bag ‘em.
他们需要更多....说服力，
总统先生。
They require more... convincing,
Mr. President.
LINCOLN: Mm-hmm.
帮我一个忙，好吗？
Do me a favor, will ya?
BILBO: 当然。
BILBO: Sure.
LINCOLN: I snagged my eye
in the paper this morning,
林肯：今天早上的报纸引起了我的注意，
Curtin州长宣称他是将是一个胜利者
and Governor Curtin is set
to declare a winner in the
将当选国会议员...
disputed Congressional election for the...
BILBO: 宾夕法尼亚州16届行政区。
BILBO: Pennsylvania 16th District.
..行政区。多么欢乐的理解啊。
.. District. What a joy
to be comprehended.
在跳往去Philadell的火车上面，
呼吁州长...
Hop on a train to Philadell,
call on the Governor...
SEWARD: 发送给Latham或者Schell。
SEWARD: Send Latham. Or Schell.
林肯：不，他会做好的，只是...
首先做好你自己的。
LINCOLN: No, he’ll do fine, just...
polish yourself up first.
[Bilbo laughs]
LATHAM:这个教区主教也在
断言他将会赢。
LATHAM: The incumbent
is claiming he won it.
LATHAM: 他的名字，呃...
– BILBO: Coffroth.
LATHAM: Name of, uh...
-林肯：这是他。
– SCHELL: Coffroth.
– LINCOLN: That’s him.
SCHELL:他是一个民主党人。
-林肯：我理解这些。
SCHELL: He is a Democrat.
– LINCOLN: I understand that.
-– BILBO: 可笑的名字。
--林肯：的确有点点可笑。
– BILBO: Silly name.
– LINCOLN: A little bit silly.
林肯：嗯，告诉Curtin 州长
它将会非常感谢
LINCOLN: Huh, Tell Governor
Curtin it’d be much appreciated
如果他被邀请这个代表议会去决定谁会赢。
if he’d invite the House of
Representatives to decide who won.
他被赋予做这个的权力。
他将会同意去做这个的。
He’s entitled to do that.
He’ll agree to it.
然后建议Coffroth，如果
他希望能保住他的位置，
Then advise Coffroth, if
he hopes to retain his seat,
你最好去拜访一下 Thaddeus Stevens.
that he’d better pay a visit
to Thaddeus Stevens.
SEWARD: 噢，可怜的Coffroth!
SEWARD: Oh, pity poor Coffroth!
[All laugh]
[Knocks on door]
STEVENS: 门开着的！
STEVENS: It opens!
STEVENS: 你是Canfrey吗？
STEVENS: You are Canfrey?
Coffroth, Mr. Stevens,
Alexander Coffroth, I’m...
STEVENS: 我们是代表相同的政府吗？
STEVENS: Are we representatives
of the same state?
是的，先生，我们的座位只相差3个桌子。
Y-yes sir, We sit only three desks apart.
STEVENS: 我没有注意到你，我...
STEVENS: I haven’t noticed you. I’m...
一个共和党人，而你，
是一个民主党人？
a Republican, and you,
Coughdrop, are a Democrat?
对....
Well...
嗯，也就是说，我...
Um, that is to say, I...
STEVENS: 这是对Thomas Jefferson政治组织最新模仿
STEVENS: The modern travesty of
Thomas Jefferson’s political organization
将你自己就像一个贝壳黏上去
to which you have attached
yourself like a barnacle
将你自己命名为民主党人。
has the effrontery to call
itself The Democratic Party.
你是一个民主党人。
You are a Dem-O-crat.
你怎么了？
你有什么事情吗？
What’s the matter with you?
Are you wicked?
嗯，我感觉，嗯，以前，我...
Well, I felt, um, formerly, I...
没关系，Coffsnot,你在这个竞选中很不光彩的责骂
Never mind, Coffsnot, you were
ignominiously trounced at the hustings
在11月份的选举中，别您的一个挑战者，一个共和党人。
in November’s election by your
worthy challenger, a Republican.
不，先生，我没有，嗯，被责骂！
No, sir, I was not, um, trounced!
嗯，他想偷走我的位置！
我不能再竞选中失败...
Uh, he wants to steal my seat!
I didn’t lose the election...
有什么区别呢，
无论是是否落选，
What difference does
it make if you lost or not,
这个国家的统治者，是...
一个民主党人？
the governor of our state, is...
A Democrat?
不，他是一个...
No, he’s a...
一个，呃，一个Ruh...
A, um, a Ruh...
Re.
- 酒吧?酒吧。
– Pub? Pub.
- 李?李。
– Li? Li.
- 可以?可以。共和主义者。
– Can? Can. Republican.
我知道他干嘛的。这只是舞文弄墨罢了。
I know what he is.his is a rhetorical exercise.
国会是什么样的组织在控制？你的？
And Congress is controlled
by what party? Yours?
你的组织被打垮了吧
Your party was beaten,
你的对手现在正在控制大局
your challenger’s party
now controls the House,
和整个选举的众议院，
and hence the House
Committee on Elections,
因此你们被打败了。
so you have been beaten.
您将在短期内被炒鱿鱼。除非......
You shall shortly be sent
home in disgrace. Unless...
我知道我必须做什么，先生，
I know what I must do, sir,
我会立刻成为一个共和党人并且投赞成票..
I will immediately become
a Republican and vote yes for...
干!
NO!
Coffroth ...会投赞成票，
Coffroth... will vote yes,
但是Coffroth仍是一个
民主党员直到他这么做了之后。
but Coffroth will remain a
Democrat until after he does so.
为什么现在不能加入？
我很乐意加入的...
Why wait to switch?
I’m happy to switch...
我们要展示的是修正案是被两党同时支持，你这个白痴。
We want to show the amendment
has bipartisan support, you idiot.
01:39:21,797 - > 01:39:25,172
下届国会快到之前，我告诉
你这样做，你就会转换党籍了。
Early in the next Congress, when I tell you to do so, you will switch parties.
现在，祝贺你胜利了，请你出去吧。
Now congratulations on your
victory, and get out.
现在...随便给我个你们曾经追踪过的名字。
Now... give me the names of
whoever else you been hunting.
乔治·耶曼。
是的。耶曼。
– LATHAM: George Yeaman.
– SCHELL: Yes. Yeaman.
BILBO：别的呢。
BILBO: Among others.
但耶曼，算是一个。
But Yeaman, that’d count.
我知道了。
– LATHAM: Y-E-A-M-A-N.
– LINCOLN: I got it.
肯塔基州。
LATHAM: Kentucky.
我不可以为该修正案投票，林肯先生。
YEAMAN: I can’t vote for the amendment, Mr. Lincoln.
我看到过一艘运输船，耶曼先生，
I saw a barge once, Mr. Yeaman,
装满了各种肤色用手链栓起来男人，
filled with colored men in chains,
沿着西西比河往下开往新奥尔良的奴隶市场。
heading down the Mississippi to the New Orleans slave markets.
整的我些许不爽。
It sickened me.
更可怕的是，它带来了阴影，
And more than that,it brought a shadow down,
我的眼睛周围了一层阴影。
a pall around my eyes.
只要我还记得奴隶制会困扰着我
Slavery troubled me as long as I can remember
在某种程度上，它从来没有困扰我的父亲，
in a way it never troubled my father,
虽然他讨厌它，按自己的方式。
though he hated it, in his own fashion.
他知道每天和脏活打交道的农夫不可能完成
像解放奴隶这样的企划。
He knew no small holding dirt farmer
could compete with slave plantations.
他把我们从肯塔基州带了出来...
He took us out from Kentucky...
..摆脱他们。他想，让印第安纳州保持自由。
to get away from ‘em.
He wanted Indiana kept free.
他不是一个善良的人，
He wasn’t a kind man,
但在公正上有些粗略的道德欲望，为了他的自由。
but there was a rough moral urge
for fairness, for freedom in him.
我从他身上学了这一点，我想，
I learnt that from him, I suppose,
即使只有一点也是
if little else from him.
我们不会相互关心，先生耶曼。
We didn’t care for one
another, Mr. Yeaman.
哦，我很抱歉听到这个消息。爱心，
– Well, I’m sorry to hear that.
– Loving kindness,
那最普通的事发生在我这
that most ordinary... thing
came to me
从其他方面..
我很感激??。
from other sources. .
I’m grateful for that.
我也讨厌它，先生...
YEAMAN: I... I hate it, too, sir...
奴隶制度，但是...
slavery, but...
但我们完全没有准备解放黑奴。
but we’re entirely unready
for emancipation.
有太多的问题...
- 我们也没有准备好迎接和平，不是吗？
There’s too many questions...
– We’re unready for peace too, ain’t we?
是的，当它来临的时候，它会以谜题的方式出现
Yeah, when it comes, it’ll present
us with conundrums and
而且比我们在战争期间面临的危险更大，血淋淋的，和它曾经一样。
dangers greater than any we’ve faced
during the war, bloody as it’s been.
我们将不得不立即适应它
和研究它
We’ll have to extemporize
and experiment with
到底是什么，什么时候来的
what it is, when it is.
我看了你的发言，乔治。
I read your speech, George.
黑人的选票的，这是一个谜。
Negroes and the vote, that's a puzzle.
不，不，但是，但是，但是
No, no, but-but-but
但黑人不能...
嗯...投票，先生林肯。
but Negroes can't...
um... vote, Mr. Lincoln.
你不是在暗示我们
解放有色人种吧
You're not suggesting we
enfranchise colored people.
我只要求你把自己从奴隶的权力中解放出来。
I'm asking only that you disenthrall
yourself from the slave powers.
我会让你知道当我的办公桌上有一份投降书时。
I'll let you know when there's
an offer on my desk for surrender.
那我们前面就没有阻碍了
There's none before us now.
什么是现在摆在我们面前，就是投票，
第十三条修正案。
What's before us now, that's the vote
on the Thirteenth Amendment.
这是迫在眉睫的
It's going to be so very close.
你看你能做些什么。
You see what you can do.
我没办法撼动它，他为了它死了。
WILLIAM HUTTON: I can’t make
sense of it, what he died for.
林肯先生，我恨他们，
确实，恨那些黑人。
Mr. Lincoln, I hate them all,
I do, all black people.
我是个有偏见的人。
I am a prejudiced man.
我想改变这种状况，如果我能。但是这不是我来的原因。
I’d change that in you if I could,
but that’s not why I come.
我可能是错的，赫顿先生，但我希望
有色人种将最有可能得到自由。
I might be wrong, Mr. Hutton, but I expect
colored people will most likely be free.
而当是这样，你哥哥的事情是简单明了的
And when that’s so, it’s simple
truth that your brother’s
勇敢，他的死，使事情这样了。
bravery, and his death, helped make it so.
只有你自己才能决定这是否满足你，或没有满足。
Only you can decide whether
that’s sense enough for you, or not.
我对您的家人表示最深切的同情。
My deepest sympathies to your family.
我们已经安排我们的成员去处理了。
PRESTON BLAIR: We’ve managed
our members to a fare thee-well.
已经没有共和党右翼的叛徒来添麻烦了。
You’ve had no defections from
the Republican right to trouble you.
而你答应的事情...
Whereas as to what you promised...
那些委员到底死哪去了？
where the hell are the commissioners?!
噢，我的上帝......这是真的！
JAMES ASHLEY: Oh my God... It’s true!
你...你骗了我，林肯先生！
You... you lied to me, Mr. Lincoln!
您以有一个同盟的和平建议来回避了我的要求
You evaded my requests for a denial that-that there is a Confederate peace offer
因为...因为有一个！
because... because there is one!
我们绝对保证会失去了整个事情！
We are absolutely guaranteed
to lose the whole thing!
我们不需要这该死的废除修订。
MONTGOMERY BLAIR: We don’t need
a goddamned abolition amendment.
抛开那发布的宪法！
阿什利：如果...如果...
M.B.: Leave the Constitution alone!
– ASHLEY: What if... what if...
..这些和平委员
今天才出现，或...
.. these peace commissioners
appear today, or...
或更糟的是，早上...
你可以逐个逐个的消灭...
ASHLEY: .. or worse, on the morning...
– M.B.: State by state you can extirpate...
我再也听不下去了
I can’t listen to this anymore.
我无法完成这该死的和人种挂钩的事情
I can’t accomplish a goddamned
thing of any human meaning
还是直到我们整好自己奴隶制，然后结束这场瘟疫战，
or worth until we cure ourselves of
slavery, and end this pestilential war,
你们中有人能够明白这一点吗，我知道我需要这个！
and whether any of you or
anyone else knows it, I know I need this!
这个修正案就是药方！
This amendment is that cure!
我们现在已经步入了世界舞台之上！
We’re stepped out upon
the world’s stage now, NOW!
随着我们手里人类尊严的命运!
尊严！
With the fate of human
dignity in our hands!
血液已经挥洒来支持这一刻！现在！
Blood’s been spilt to afford us
this moment! Now now now!
但是，你埋怨，疑惑和闪躲
But you grouse and heckle and dodge about
就像欺诈坦慕尼协会的小贩！
like pettifogging Tammany Hall hucksters!
看看在你面前的是什么！
See what is before you!
看看这里，看看现在！
这才是最麻烦的事情，
See the here and now!
That’s the hardest thing,
唯一算得上的一件事！
the only thing that accounts!
通过临时宪法来废除奴隶制度，
Abolishing slavery by
constitutional provision
处理别人的命运，为了我们的未来，
settles the fate, for all coming time,
不仅仅是现在数十万的奴役
not only of the millions now in bondage
还有未来数十万要出生的婴儿
but of unborn millions to come.
两种选择各以各的方式孤立，
Two votes stand in its way,
这些选票我们必须拿到！
and these votes must be procured!
我们需要两个赞成，
三票弃权，或
We need two yeses,
three abstentions, or
或者四个赞成和一票弃权这将通过和修订。
four yeses and one more abstention
and the amendment will pass.
你得到了一个晚上和一个白天和一个晚上
和好几个小时，
You got a night and a day and a night
and several perfectly good hours,
现在滚出这里，并得把这个处理好！
now get the hell out of here and get ‘em!
是啊。但怎么做呢？
ASHLEY: Yes. But how?
勇敢的人
Buzzards’ guts, man.
我是美国的主席，
I am the President of the
United States of America,
有着巨大的力量！
clothed in immense power!
你会给我弄到这些选票的。
You will procure me these votes.
我们欢迎你 女士们，先生们，
LITTON: We welcome you,
ladies and gentlemen,
在这个房子里面的伟大历史壮举，为了你们的家园
first in the history of this
people’s chamber, to your House!
阿什利先生，舞台是你的
COLFAX: Mr. Ashley, the floor is yours.
关于我们商议的那个联合决议，
ASHLEY: On the matter of
the joint resolution before us,
对我国宪法提议的第十三条修正案，
presenting a Thirteenth Amendment
to our national Constitution,
那个去年已经被参议院通过，
which was passed last year by the Senate,
那个一直被争论不休，在过去的几个星期中这难能可贵的躯体经过打磨，
and which has been debated now by this
estimable body for the past several weeks,
今天，我们将投票...
today we will vote...
[欢呼声，嘘声，掌声]
[Cheers, boos, applause]
经双方协议，我们应听到简短最后的陈述，
By mutual agreement, we shall
hear brief final statements,
从光荣的乔治·彭德尔顿开始，来自俄亥俄州。
beginning with the honorable
George Pendleton of Ohio.
我刚刚收到
PENDLETON: I’ve just received
确认书
confirmation
曾经只是个传说的它！
of what previously has been merely rumored!
宣誓书！
Affidavits!
最近从忠诚的公民返回到里士满。
From loyal citizens recently
returned from Richmond.
他们作证说，委员们已经确定
They testify that
Commissioners have indeed
要来北部，应该到华盛顿市了现在，
come north and ought to have
arrived by now in Washington City,
忍受着一张立刻让我们停止内战的提议书！
bearing an offer of immediate
cessation of our civil war!
[室爆炸]
[The chamber explodes]
这是真的吗，先生？
WOOD: Is it true, sir?
有同盟委员在国会大厦？
WOOD: Are there Confederate
commissioners in the Capitol?
我不...我不知道他们在哪里，如果他们已经抵达。
ASHLEY: I don’t... I have no idea
where they are or if they’ve arrived.
如果他们已经来了？！
WOOD: If they’ve arrived?!
我呼吁我的民主党同僚，
PENDLETON: I appeal to
my fellow Democrats,
和所有给予无花果和和平的共和党代表！
to all Republican representatives
who give a fig for peace!
推迟投票，直到我们有总统本人的答案！
Postpone this vote until we have
answers from the President himself!
[民主党人开始呗]
推迟投票！推迟投票！
[ Democrats begin to chant]
Postpone the vote! Postpone the vote!
推迟投票！
Postpone the vote!
哈德姆，先生们！
AARON HADDAM: Gentlemen!
我知道怎么做了！
WOOD: I have made a motion!
这里有没有人关心我的提议？
Does anyone here care to second my motion?
[民主党人仍然高呼]
推迟投票！推迟投票！
[ Democrats still shouting]
Postpone the vote! Postpone the vote!
君子。
HADDAM: Gentlemen.
保守派边境和西部的共和党
The conservative faction of
border and western Republicans
不可以批准这项修正，
cannot approve this amendment,
这个我们还抱有很大的疑虑...
about which we harbor grave doubts...
如果和平建议被成功的挟持。
if a peace offer is being held hostage to its success.
考虑到我们民主人士们，我考虑这个议案推迟。
Joining together with our Democratic
colleagues, I second the motion to postpone.
[比尔博曼波斯]
快速，伙计！快！
[Bilbo mumbles]
LATHAM: Quick, man! Quick!
这正是伍德先生希望我来回答吗？
LINCOLN: This is precisely what
Mr. Wood wishes me to respond to?
就说的话，这的确是是他对我的要求吗？
Word for word, this is precisely the
assurance that he demands of me?
是的，先生。
BILBO: Yes sir.
把这个给先生阿什利。
Give this to Mr. Ashley.
我觉得，嗯，我说，林肯先生，这...
JOHN HAY: I feel, um, I have
to say, Mr. Lincoln, that this...
能否请您你们出去走走？
Could you please just step outside?!
你要现在要聊天吧，
You gonna have a chat now,
整个众议院代表都在等这个？
with the whole of the House of
Representatives waiting on that?
向国会做出错误的陈述是...
Making false representation
to Congress is...
这是，这是......
- 这是可控告的。
It’s, it’s...
– It's Impeachable.
我还没有给出虚假的陈述。
I’ve made no false representation.
但也有！
But there are!
有里士满的代表团。
There is a delegation from Richmond.
把那个给我，杜琪峰。
LINCOLN: Give me the note, Johnnie.
请交付先生阿什利。
Please deliver that to Mr. Ashley.
来自从总统先生：
ASHLEY: From the President:
“据我所知，在这个城市没有和平委员
“So far as I know, there are no
peace commissioners in the city
也没有其他性质的组织”。
nor are there likely to be”.
“据我所知”？
PENDLETON: “So far as I know”?!
这意味着什么都没有！
That means nothing!
有委员来自南方或一个都没有吗？
Are there commissioners from
the South or aren’t there?!
总统已经回答了你，先生。
ASHLEY: The President
has answered you, sir.
你的和平建议是虚构的！
Your peace offer is a fiction!
这是不是拒绝，
PENDLETON: That is not a denial,
它是一个律师的闪避！
it is a lawyer’s dodge!
哈丹姆，你的阵营满意吗？
ASHLEY: Mr. Haddam,
is your faction satisfied?
保守的共和党派满意了，
The conservative Republican
faction’s satisfied,
我们感谢林肯先生。
and we thank Mr. Lincoln.
我谨表木先生的议案。
I move to table Mr. Wood’s motion.
赞同！
COLFAX: Tabled!
议长科尔，我列出了主要问题。
ASHLEY: Speaker Colfax,
I order the main question.
第十三条修正案的投票已经有一个议案来促使了。
A motion has been made to bring the bill
for the Thirteenth Amendment to a vote.
有人支持吗？我支持提议。
Do I hear a second?
–  LITTON: I second the motion.
太感动了，这样有序。
COLFAX: So moved, so ordered.
店员会现在...
请保持安静。
The Clerk will now...
Quiet please.
店员会点名开始投票
COLFAX: The clerk will now
call the roll for the voting.
“我们从康涅狄格开始。奥古斯都本杰明先生，
CLERK: We begin with Connecticut.
Mr. Augustus Benjamin,
关于修订的问题，你怎么看？
on the matter of this
amendment, how say you?
我的天！
Nay!
“阿瑟先生Bentleigh？ 我的天！
– CLERK: Mr. Arthur Bentleigh.
– Nay!
约翰·埃利斯先生，你怎么说？
CLERK: Mr. John Ellis, how say you?
赞成！  靠，有病啊？
– Aye!
– A DEMOCRAT: What?
[的科尔gavels为为了]
[Colfax gavels for order]
秘书：密苏里州的接着。沃尔特 阿尔普顿先生。
CLERK: Missouri next. Mr. Walter Appleton.
我投反对票！
I vote no!
“约西亚·伯顿先生。”
CLERK: Mr. Josiah Burton.
Beanpole伯顿高兴地投票 赞成！
Beanpole Burton is pleased to vote yea!
新泽西州，尼佳先生。
CLERk: The State of New Jersey.
Mr. Nehemiah Cleary.
不!
No.
先生马丁森。
CLERK: Mr. James Martinson.
马丁森先生已委派我
ASHLEY: Mr. Martinson has delegated me
说他是身体不适...
弃权。
to say he is indisposed...
and he abstains.
奥斯汀J.罗伯茨先生。身体不适，也弃权。
– Mr. Austin J. Roberts.
– Also indisposed, also abstaining.
伊利诺伊州的结束呢。
CLERK: Illinois concluded.
哈罗德·霍利斯特先生，你怎么说？
- 不
CLERK: Mr. Harold Hollister, how say you?
– No.
先生赫顿？
CLERK: Mr. Hutton?
威廉·赫顿，投你的票。
Mr. William Hutton, cast your vote.
威廉·赫顿，记住在这时刻他心爱的弟弟弗雷德里克，
William Hutton, remembering at this
moment his beloved brother Fredrick,
反对。
votes against the amendment.
韦伯斯特艾伦投反对。
SOLDIER: Webster Allen votes no.
[电缆电报点击]
[Cable telegraph clicking]
[阅读]韦伯斯特艾伦...
伊利诺伊州...民主党...票...
[READING] Webster Allen...
Illinois... Democrat... votes...
[电缆电报不断点击]
反对。
[Cable telegraph keeps clicking]
No.
戟法...印第安纳州...
民主党...票...反对。
Halberd Law... Indiana...
Democrat... votes... no.
[警长继续阅读，因为它涉及]
阿奇博尔德·莫兰...
[Sergeant keeps reading as it comes]
Archibald Moran...
赞成。
Yes.
刘汉铨拜勒...赞成。
Ambrose Bailer... yes.
– CLERK: Mr. Walter H. Washburn.
Walter H. Washburn先生
– Votes no.
投反对
And Mr. George Yeaman, how say you?
George Yeaman先生，您的投票？
[Total silence]
[Yeaman mumbles inaudibly]
Sorry Mr. Yeaman, I didn’t hear you vote.
抱歉Yeaman先生，我没听到您的投票
I said aye, Mr. McPherson.
我说了赞成， McPherson先生
AAAAAYE!!!
– WOOD: Traitor!
叛徒！
WOOD: Traitor!
–  COLFAX: Order!
肃静！
COLFAX: Order in that chamber!
保持厅内秩序
COLFAX: Mr. MacPherson, you may proceed.
MacPherson先生，你可以继续了
CLERK: Mr. Clay R. Hawkins of Ohio.
来自俄亥俄州的Clay R.先生
Goddamn it, I’m voting yes.
去他大爷的，我投赞同票
I don’t care, shoot me dead!
You shoot me dead, I-I am voting yes!
无所谓，有本事打我啊，你打我，我还是赞同！
CLERK: Mr. Edwin F. LeClerk.
Edwin F. LeClerk先生
No!
反对
Oh to hell with it,
shoot me dead too. Yes!
噢，让它见鬼去吧，也打死我，都要赞同！
LECLERK: I mean...
Abstention. Abstention.
我是说...
弃权，弃权
CLERK: Mr. Alexander Coffroth.
Alexander Coffroth先生
I... Vote... Yes.
我...投...赞同
[Cable clicking, Sergeant reading]
Yea.
赞同
James... Brooks...
James... Brooks...（两个人吗）
Nay.
反对
Josiah... Grinnell...
Josiah... Grinnell...（两个人名）
Yea.
赞同
Meyer... Straus...
Meryer...Straus（两个人名）
– Nay.
反对
– CLERK: Mr. Joseph Marstern?
Joseph Marstern先生
– Nay.
不同意
– Mr. Chilton A. Elliot?
Chilton A. Elliot先生呢？
– No!
否
– Mr. Daniel G. Stuart?
Daniel G. Stuart先生
– I vote yes.
我投...赞同！
– Mr. Howard Guilefoyle.
Howard Guilefoyle先生
– Yea.
赞同
– John F. McKenzie.
John F. McKenzie（人名）
– Yea.
同意
– Andrew E. Fink.
Andrew E. Fink（人名）
– Nay.
反对
– Mr. John A. Kassim.
John A. Kassim 先生
– Yea.
赞同
– Mr. Hanready.
Hanready 先生
– Nay.
反对
– And Mr. Rufus Warren?
Rufus Warren先生呢？
– Yea.
赞同票
CLERK: The roll call concludes,
投票结束
voting is completed, now...
计票结束，现在...
COLFAX: Mr. Clerk...
Clerk先生...
Please call my name.
I want to cast a vote.
请喊我的名字，我想投一票
PENDLETON: I object!
我反对
The Speaker doesn’t vote!
主持不能参与投票！
COLFAX: The Speaker
may vote if he so chooses.
如果主持人愿意，他可以投票
It is highly unusual, sir.
先生，
这次投票是史无前例的
This isn’t usual, Mr. Pendleton.
This is history.
CLERK: How does Mr. Schuyler Colfax vote?
Schuyler Colfax先生，您怎么投...
Aye, of course.
当然是赞成了
The final vote.
最终结果
eight absent or not voting,
八位缺席，或弃权
fifty six votes against,
五十六票反对
one hundred nineteen votes for,
一百一十九票赞成
with a margin of two votes...
两票中立
[Bells begin to peal throughout the city]
[Bells are joined by a cannonade]
[Representatives applaude, weep, shout, dance, yell]
Ashley, this time we've made it!
Ashley，我们这次成功了！
CLERk: Congratulations, Mr. Chairman.
祝贺您，主席
With the bill, Mr. McPherson, may I...?
McPherson先生，
能让我看一下议案纸吗？
CLERK: That's... that’s the official bill.
这是...正式提案？
I’ll return it in the morning.
我明早就还你
Creased...
but unharmed.
点皱了，但保证不会有损
STEVENS: A gift for you.
有个礼物给你
STEVENS: The greatest measure
of the Nineteenth Century,
美国十九世纪最为伟大的举措
passed by corruption, aided and
abetted by the purest man in America.
因贿赂而得以通过，
但又被美国最为纯洁的人所净化
Aah, I wish you’d been present.
阿，真希望你也到场
– LYDIA SMITH: I wish I’d been.
我也希望
– It was a spectacle.
那场面太壮观
LYDIA: You can’t bring
your housekeeper to the House.
你不能把一个女管家带进议院
I won’t give them gossip.
This is enough.
我不会让他们说闲话的，已经够了
This is...
这是...
It’s more than enough for now.
对现在来说这样就够了
STEVENS: Read it to me again, my love.
再为我读一遍，亲
LYDIA: “Proposed”...
“提议”
– And adopted.
– Adopted.
并通过
- 通过
“An Amendment to the Constitution
of the United States.
“美利坚合众国宪法修正案”
Section One: Neither slavery nor
involuntary servitude,
第一款 苦役或强迫劳役，
except as a punishment for crime
除用以惩罚
whereof the party shall
have been duly convicted,
依法判刑的罪犯之外
shall exist within the United States,
不得在合众国境内
or any place subject
to their jurisdiction.”
或受合众国管辖之任何地方存在。"
– Section Two.
– “Congress shall have power
第二款
- 国会有权力
to enforce this amendment
by appropriate legislation.”
通过恰当的立法强制本条实施。
[All cheer Lincoln’s arrival]
所有人都为林肯总得的到来而欢呼雀跃
ALEXANDER STEPHENS:
Let me be blunt.
恕我直言
Will the southern states resume
their former position in the Union
南方诸州是否会尽快恢复
在合众国内的先前地位
speedily enough to enable us to block
ratification of the Thirteenth Amendment?
以帮助我们阻止十三号修正案的生效呢？
LINCOLN: I’d like peace immediately.
我希望我们立刻议和
STEPHENS: Yes, and...?
那么...？
LINCOLN: I’d like your states restored
我希望南方诸州
to their practical relations
to the Union immediately.
能够立刻恢复先前在合众国中的地位
If this could be given me in writing,
as Vice President of the Confederacy,
如果能在条约内加上这一项，
作为南方邦联的副总统
I’d bring that document
with celerity to Jefferson Davis.
我将以最快速度将文件
递交给Jefferson Davis 总统
SEWARD: Surrender, and
we can discuss reconstruction.
投降，然后我们再谈重建的问题
Surrender won’t be thought of
除非你们能以书面形式
unless you’ve assured us, in writing,
让我们保证及时恢复我们
that we’ll be readmitted in
time to block this amendment.
以抵制这项修正案的生效的话，
我们便不考虑议和
HUNTER: This is the arrogant
demand of a conqueror.
对于胜利方来说提出这样的请求
未免有些傲慢自大了吧
SEWARD: You’ll not be a conquered
people, Mr. Hunter, you will be citizens.
你们并非被战败方，Hunter先生，
你们仍是美国公民
Returned to the laws and the
guarantees of rights of the Constitution.
重新受到法律的束缚
并获得宪法保障的公民权利
Which now extinguishes slavery.
And with it our economy.
宪法现在废除了奴隶制，
我们的经济
All our laws will be determined by
a Congress of vengeful Yankees,
我们的法律
都由一群心怀不满的北方人所决定
all our rights’ll be subject
to a Supreme Court
我们的所有权利都将受到最高法院的管制
benched by Black Republican radicals.
里面坐满了共和党的黑人激进分子
All our traditions will be obliterated.
我们的传统将不复存在
We won’t know ourselves anymore.
我们都不再记得自己曾经是谁了
We ain’t here to discuss reconstruction,
我们不是来谈重建事宜的
we have no legal basis
for that discussion.
关于这点我们没有法律基础
But I don’t want to deal falsely.
但我不想做虚伪的交易
The Northern states’ll ratify,
most of ‘em.
北方诸州中的大多数
会让这一修正案生效的
As I figure, it remains for two of
the Southern states to do the same,
据我统计，南方还有两个州亟待执行法案
even after all are readmitted.
即便在所有的州重新加入联邦之后也一样
And I been working on that.
我会为之采取进一步举措的
Tennessee and Louisiana.
田纳西州和路易斯安那州
Arkansas too, most likely.
It’ll be ratified.
阿肯萨斯州也有可能
Slavery, sir... it’s done.
至于奴隶制，先生...已经结束了
If we submit ourselves to law, Alex,
如果我们把自身交由法律管束，Alex
even submit to losing freedoms...
哪怕就此失去一些自由
the freedom to oppress, for instance...
比如，失去压迫他人的自由
we may discover other freedoms
previously unknown to us.
我们或许能发现
其它前所未见的自由权利
Had you kept faith with
democratic process,
你们还相信民主进程
as frustrating as that can be...
– CAMPBELL: Come sir,
够了，先生
spare us at least these pieties.
收起这套虚伪的面孔吧
Did you defeat us with ballots?
你们以选举的方式击败了我们吗？
STEPHENS: How’ve you held your Union together?
你们是怎样将联邦团结起来的？
Through democracy?
通过民主？
How many hundreds of thousands
have died during your administration?
在您的任期内究竟死了多少人？
Your Union, sir, is bonded
in cannon fire and death.
您的联邦，先生，是由炮火和鲜血堆积的
LINCOLN: It may be you’re right.
也许你说的对
But say all we done is show
the world that democracy isn’t chaos,
但我们所做的一切皆是在向世界昭示，
民主并非暴乱
that there is a great invisible
strength in a people’s union?
在人民的联邦间
存在一种伟大的力量将其维系吗？
Say we’ve shown that a people can
endure awful sacrifice and yet cohere?
然而人民在做出巨大的牺牲之后
不是仍旧团结一致吗？
Mightn’t that save at least the
idea of democracy to aspire to?
至少值得追求的民主
不是就此被拯救了吗？
Eventually, to become worthy of?
最终这一切不是都展现出其价值了吗
At all rates, whatever may be
proven by blood and sacrifice
无论如何，那些流血与牺牲所能证明的
must’ve been proved by now.
都已在当下得证
Shall we stop this bleeding?
我们可以停止这场流血的战争了吗？
LINCOLN: Once he surrenders, send
his boys back to their homes,
一旦他投降，
就把那些孩子送回他们的家
their farms, their shops.
他们的农庄，他们的作坊
GRANT: Yes sir... as we discussed.
好的，先生...就像我们之前说好的那样
LINCOLN: Liberality all around.
No punishment. I don’t want that.
所有的人都将获得自由，没有惩罚，
我不想看到
And the leaders -Jeff
and the rest of ‘em...
那些领头人——Jeff还有剩下的那些
...
if they escape, leave the
country while my back’s turned,
如果他们在我不注意时逃离了这个国家
that wouldn’t upset me none.
那才是我会感担心的事
When peace comes
it mustn’t just be hangings.
我们追求的是真正而非表面的和平
By outward appearance,
从外表上看
you’re ten years older
than you were a year ago.
您比一年前要老了十岁
Some weariness has bit at my bones.
我身上的每一块骨头都感觉极度疲惫
I never seen the like of it before.
What I seen today.
我今天看到的一切
给了我从没有过的感觉
Never seen the like of it before.
从没有过
GRANT: You always knew that...
what this was going to be.
你知道的...它接下来会如何发展
Intimate, and ugly.
美好却又丑陋
You must’ve needed to see it close
when you decided to come down here.
在你决定来这里之前你一定急需想看看这幅画面
LINCOLN: We’ve made it possible
for one another to do terrible things.
我们让自相残杀变得可能
GRANT: And we’ve won the war.
并且我们赢得了这场战争的胜利
Now you have to lead us out of it.
现在你不许带领我们走出它
You’ve an itch to travel?
你想去旅行吗
I’d like that.
我很乐意
To the West by rail.
搭乘火车去西部
Overseas.
去海外吧
The Holy Land.
去圣地
Awfully pious for a man who takes
his wife out buggy-riding on Good Friday.
在耶稣的受难日带着妻子坐马车出行的男人要是多么虔诚的信徒
Jerusalem.
耶路撒冷
Where David and Solomon walked.
那David 和Solomon走过的土地
I dream of... walking
in that ancient city.
我梦想着...漫步在那座古城中
All anyone will remember of me is
I was crazy and I ruined your happiness.
每个人都会记得我是那样疯狂并
毁掉了你的幸福
Anyone thinks that
doesn’t understand, Molly.
那样想的人是不会理解我们的，Molly
When they look at you,
当他们看着你的时候
at what it cost to live
at the heart of this,
他们会好奇，带着这样的一颗心生活
they’ll wonder at it. They’ll
wonder at you, they should.
他们会好奇的，他们也理应好奇
But they should also look
at the wretched woman by your side,
他们理所应当看看身边这个不幸的女人
if they want to understand
what this was truly like.
如果他们想知道这些的话
For the ordinary person.
For anyone other than you.
为了人民，
为了你之外的所有人
We must try to be happier.
我们必须试着变得快乐
We must. Both of us.
我们必须这么做，我俩都是
We’ve been so miserable for so long.
我们过了这么久悲惨的日子
LINCOLN: I did say some colored men,
我确实讲到了一部分有色人种中的男性
the intelligent, the educated,
and veterans, I qualified it.
那些受过教育的，退伍军人，
我授予他们这项权利
ASHLEY: Mr. Stevens is furious,
he wants to know why you qualified it.
Stevens先生很生气，
他想知道您授予这项权利的原因
COLFAX: No one's heard the
intelligent or the educated part.
没人听说过“受过教育”这一部分
All they heard was the first time
any president has ever made mention
他们闻知的就是
史上第一次有总统提及
of Negro voting.
要给与黑人投票权
LINCOLN: Still, I wish I had
mentioned it in a better speech.
我希望我能在一次更好的演说中
提及这件事
ASHLEY: Mr. Stevens also wants to know
why you didn’t make a better speech.
Stevens先生也想知道
您为什么没有发表一次更出色的演说
NICOLAY: Mrs. Lincoln’s
waiting in the carriage.
林肯夫人在车上等您
She wants me to remind you of the hour,
她想我给您提醒一下时间
and that you’ll have to pick up
Miss Harris and Major Rathbone.
您还得去接Harris小姐和Rathbone市长
– LINCOLN: Am I in trouble?
我惹麻烦了吗
– SLADE: No, sir.
还没有
Thank you, Mr. Slade.
非常感谢你，slade先生
LINCOLN: I suppose it’s time to go,
我想我该走了
though I would rather stay.
尽管我更想呆在这里
OWNER OF THE THEATER:
The President has been shot!
总统遭到了枪击！
The President has been
shot at Ford’s Theater!
总统在福特剧院遭到了枪击！
DR. BARNES: It’s... 7:22 in the morning,
现在是...清晨七点二十二分
Saturday the 15th of April.
It’s all over.
四月十五日，周六，病人宣告死亡
The President is no more.
总统去世了
STANTON: Now he belongs to the ages.
现在他成了历史的一部分
LINCOLN: Fondly do we hope,
fervently do we pray,
我们天真地盼望，热诚地祷告
that this mighty scourge of war
may speedily pass away.
这场惩罚性的战争
已经迅速地远离我们远去
Yet, if God wills that it continue
然而，如果神执意让战争持续下去
until all the wealth piled by
the bondman's
直到从所有财富被奴隶堆积
two hundred and fifty years
of unrequited toil shall be sunk,
在这两百五十年间困苦劳动之下所累积的财富毁去
and until every drop of
blood drawn with the lash
直到每一滴血迹绘出的皮鞭
shall be paid by another
drawn with the sword,
被还请给下每一条冤魂
as was said three thousand years ago,
so still it must be said
就如古人在三千年前所说，
而今天仍要延叙
"the judgments of the Lord are
true and righteous altogether.”
主的审判信实，合乎公义
With malice toward none,
不以恶待人
with charity for all,
以宽容包容对人
with firmness in the right as
God gives us to see the right,
神开启我们的眼让我们看见公义
let us strive on to finish
the work we are in,
让我们全力以赴，完成我们所有的工作
to bind up the nation's wounds,
治疗国家的伤口
to care for him who shall
have borne the battle,
照料在战役中忍受苦痛的人
and for his widow and his orphan,
和那些寡妇、孤儿
to do all which may achieve and cherish
不忘记珍惜爱护他们
a just and a lasting peace among ourselves
让我们之间竭尽全力维持一个和平
and with all nations.
与所有的国家
Download Movie Subtitles Searcher from www.podnapisi.net